（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
好啦，咱们开始上课
I'd like to get started today we're
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
今天咱们谈谈 GFS
gonna talk about GFS the Google file
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
也就是就是今天我们要读的论文《The Google File System》
system paper we read for today
这也是在咱们这门课里
and this will be the first of a number
众多 case 里要学的第一篇
of different sort of case studies we'll
关于如何构建大型存储的文章
talk about in this course about how to
be build big storage systems so the
这里“大型存储”是一个很大的话题
larger topic is big storage the reason
为什么是存储？
is the storage is turned out to be a key
因为存储被证明是一种关键抽象
abstraction you might you know if you
如果你还不知道的话
didn't know already you might imagine
你可以想象在分布式系统中
that there could be all kinds of
你希望使用的各种不同的抽象
different you know important
abstractions you might want to use for
但事实表明
distributed systems but it's turned out
简单的存储接口往往更有用而且更加通用
that a simple storage interface is just
incredibly useful and extremely general
构建分布式系统
and so a lot of the thought that's gone
大多都是关于如何设计存储系统
into building distributed systems has
或是设计其它类型的系统
either gone into designing storage
在它的底层
systems or designing other systems that
运行着一个不错的大型分布式存储系统
assume underneath them some sort of
reasonably well behaved big just
运行着一个不错的大型分布式存储系统
distributed storage system so we're
所以我们会更加关注
going to care a lot about how the you
如何为大型分布式存储系统设计一个优秀的接口
know how to design a good interface to a
big storage system and how to design the
以及如何设计存储系统的内部结构
innards of the storage system so it has
这样它才具备良好的行为
good behavior you know of course that's
通过阅读这篇论文可以让我们起步
why we're reading this paper is to get
a start on that. the this paper also
论文也涉及到很多本课程常出现的话题
touches on a lot of themes that will
come up a lot in a tube for parallel
主要包括并行性能、容错、复制和一致性
performance fault tolerance replication
and consistency and this paper is as
论文的内容也像 Go 语言那样，简单明了
such things go reasonably
straightforward and easy to understand
这也是一篇非常优秀的系统论文
it's also a good systems paper it sort
从硬件到软件
of talks about issues all the way from
到最终构建出整个系统都有涉及
the hardware to the software that
ultimately uses the system and it's a
而且在现实世界中 它也设计的相当成功
successful real world design so it says
尽管这是在学术会议上发表的论文
you know academic paper published in an
academic conference but it describes
但是文章里介绍的东西(GFS)也相当成功
something that really was successful and
在现实世界中也使用了相当长的时间
used for a long time in the real world
所以，在这里
so we sort of know that we're talking
咱们讨论的这些东西 真的相当牛逼
about something that is it's a good a
good useful design okay so before I'm
不过在讨论 GFS 前
gonna talk about GFS I want to sort of
我想聊聊一点关于分布式存储系统的空间
talk about the space of distributed
storage systems a little bit
首先 为什么它会如此之难？
to set the scene so first why is it hard
你需要做大量的工作才能让他变得正确
it's actually a lot to get right but for
但在 6.824 里
824 there's a particular sort of
会有一些特殊的讲述方式
narrative that's gonna come up quite a
在未来很多系统里你将会接触到
lot for many systems often the starting
人们设计大型分布式系统
point for people designing these sort of
或大型存储系统 通常的出发点是
big distributed systems or big storage
为了获得巨大的综合性能
systems is they want to get huge
aggregate performance be able to harness
要能利用数百台机器的资源 来完成大量工作
the resources of hundreds of machines in
order to get a huge amount of work done
因此 性能问题就成为了最初的诉求
so the sort of starting point is often
performance and you know if you start
因此有个很自然的想法
there a natural next thought is well
将数据进行分割 放到大量服务器上
we're gonna split our data over a huge
number of servers in order to be able to
从而能够并行地 从多台服务器读取数据
read many servers in parallel so we're
通常 我们把这种方式称为 分片(sharding)
gonna get and that's often called
如果你将数据分片到成百上千台服务器上
sharding if you shard over many servers
hundreds or thousands of servers you're
你会发现出错成了常态
just gonna see constant faults right if
在上千台服务器中 总有那么几台会宕机
you have thousands of servers there's
just always gonna be one down so we
所以每天 每小时都在发生错误
the faults are just every day every hour
所以 我们需要自动化的方法去纠正它
occurrences and we need automatic
你不可能靠人工去发现并纠正这些错误
we can't have human involved and fixing
所以 得需要有一个自动化的 容错(fault-tolerant, ft)系统
this fault we need automatic
fault-tolerant systems so that leads to
这就引出 容错 这个话题
fault tolerance the among the most
实现容错最有用的一种方法是使用复制
powerful ways to get fault tolerance is
with replication just keep two or three
只需保留两三个或更多数量数据副本
or whatever copies of data one of them
只要其中有一个失败，你就可以使用另一个
fails you can use another one so we want
所以，如果想要容错能力，就得有 复制（replication）
to have tolerance that leads to
如果有复制 两份数据的副本
replication if you have replication two
copies the data then you know for sure
可以确定的是 如果你不小心 它们就会不一致
if you're not careful they're gonna get
所以如果你有 2 个数据副本（replicas）
out of sync and so what you thought was
你就能使用其中之一替换另一个 进行容错
two replicas of the data where you could
use either one interchangeably to
你就能使用其中之一替换另一个 进行容错
tolerate faults if you're not careful
如果你不小心弄出两个几乎不同的 replicas
what you end up with is two almost
identical replicas of the data that's
严格来讲它们就算不上 replicas
like not exactly replicas at all and
那么 你获得的数据 将取决于与向哪个服务器请求
what you get back depends on which one
you talk to so that's starting to maybe
这样的话 应用程序用起来就有点棘手
look a little bit
tricky for applications to use so if we
所以如果采用复制 就可能遇到奇怪的不一致问题
have replication we risk weird
inconsistencies of course clever design
当然 有聪明的设计 可以让你避免不一致
you can get rid of inconsistency and
并使数据看起来是行为良好的
make the data look very well-behaved but
但这种设计的代价是 你得做更多额外的工作
if you do that it almost always requires
extra work and extra sort of chitchat
以及网络中所有不同服务器和客户端之间的额外通信
between all the different servers and
clients in the network that reduces
这样性能也就变低了
performance so if you want consistency
因此 如果要保持一致性 你的性能就会变低
you pay for with low performance I which
当然这也违背了我们的初衷
is of course not what we originally
当然这是绝对的
hoping for of course this is an absolute
你可以构建 高性能的系统
you can build very high performance
在设计这些系统的时候 这些事情你都需要去面对
systems but nevertheless there's this
sort of inevitable way that the design
在设计这些系统的时候 这些事情你都需要去面对
of these systems play out and it results
所以这就会导致你需要在
in a tension between the original goals
性能目标和实现良好的一致性之间做权衡
of performance and the sort of
realization that if you want good
并因此付出一些代价
consistency you're gonna pay for it and
如果你不想付出代价 那你就得接受系统的异常行为
if you don't want to pay for it then you
have to suffer with sort of anomalous
我把这些东西写在这里
behavior sometimes I'm putting this up
因为在未来许多系统里 你都能经常见到这些东西
because we're gonna see this this loop
many times for many of the systems we
有很多人都不太愿意在良好的一致性（强一致性）上面花费精力
look we look at people are rarely
willing to or happy about paying the
有很多人都不太愿意在良好的一致性（强一致性）上面花费精力
full cost of very good consistency ok so
在接下来的课程里我将会讨论更多关于良好一致性的话题
you know with brought a consistency I'll
talk more later in the course about more
在接下来的课程里我将会讨论更多关于良好一致性的话题
exactly what I mean by good consistency
你可以把“强一致性”(strong consistency)
but you can think of strong consistency
或是“良好一致性”的系统想象成就像是一台单机 server 一样
or good consistency as being we want to
build a system whose behavior to
应用程序或是客户端和它通信，感觉就像是和一台 server 通信
applications or clients looks just like
you'd expect from talking to a single
应用程序或是客户端和它通信，感觉就像是和一台 server 通信
server all right we're gonna build you
在数百台机器上的构建的理想的强一致模型的系统
know systems out of hundreds of machines
but a kind of ideal strong consistency
在同一时刻你只能请求到一台 server 上的一个数据副本
model would be what you'd get if there
was just one server with one copy of the
在同一时刻你只能请求到一台 server 上的一个数据副本
data doing one thing at a time so this
这是思考强一致的一种最直觉的方式
is kind of a strong
consistency kind of intuitive way to
这是思考强一致的一种最直觉的方式
think about strong consistency so you
你可以想象你有一台服务器
might think you have one server we'll
这里假设它是单线程服务
assume that's a single-threaded server
在同一时刻它处理来自多个客户端的请求
and that it processes requests from
clients one at a time and that's
这很重要，因为有大量客户端可能会同时并发的请求 server
important because there may be lots of
clients sending concurrently requests
server 看到这些请求后
into the server and see some current
首先会从中挑选一个出来
requests it picks one or the other to go
first and excute that request to
处理请求结束后 然后继续处理下一个
completion then excute the next so for
对于存储服务来说 你知道它会有一块磁盘
storage servers or you know the server's
got a disk on it and what it means to
这意味着处理一条请求可能会写入一条 item
process a request is it's a write
request you know which might be writing
也可能是给某个 item 做自增
an item or may be increment and I mean
这里自增一个 item 是指它是否是一个可修改操作
incrementing an item if it's a mutation
我有一些数据记录在这个表中
then we're gonna go and we have some
它可能是通过 key-value 进行索引的数据
table of data and you know maybe index
by keys and values and we're gonna
然后我们打算更新这个表
update this table and if the request
如果一条请求进来读取它
comes in and to read we're just gonna
只需要把写入的数据拉出来就行了
you know pull the write data out of the
这里有一条法则
table one of the rules here that sort of
要想使得 server 行为良好
makes this well-behaved is that each is
那么 server 必须以一种简单的模型去运行
that the server really does execute in
即同一时刻，只处理一条请求
our simplified model excuse to request
one at a time and that requests see data
任何请求看到的数据
that reflects all the previous
都能反应出在这之前所有的有序的操作
operations in order so if a sequence of
所以 如果有一系列的写操作请求同时到来
writes come in and the server process
server 就会有序的处理它们
them in some order then when you read
当你读取的时候 你就能读取到你期望的值
you see the sort of you know value you
would expect if those writes that
当你读取的时候 你就能读取到你期望的值
occurred one at a time the behavior this
这个行为仍然没那么简单
is still not completely straightforward
你不得不花上几秒的时间去考虑一些事情
there's some you know there's some
things that you have to spend at least a
你不得不花上几秒的时间去考虑一些事情
second thinking about so for example if
比如我们有几个客户端
we have a bunch of clients and client
客户端 C1 发起写请求写 x 并把它的值设置成 1
one issues a write of value X and wants
it to set it to one and at the same time
在同一时刻 客户端 C2 发起请求也写 x
client two issues the right of the same
但是它想把值设置成一个不同的值(2)
value but wants to set it to a different
the same key but wants to set it to a
但是它想把值设置成一个不同的值(2)
different value right
现在有别的事情发生了
something happens let's say client three
客户端 C3 请求读并得到一个结果
reads and get some result or client
或者说 C3 在写请求结束后读取会得到一个结果
three after these writes complete reads
get some result client four
客户端 C4 读取 x 也得到一个结果
reads X and get some also gets a result
那么这两个客户端看到的结果是多少？
so what results should the two clients
(提问)
see yeah
很好，这个问题不错
well that's a good question so these
这里的客户端 C1 和 C2
what I'm assuming here is that client
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
我假设它们是在同时发起的请求
one and client two launch these requests at
如果监控网络的话 我们能看到 2 个请求同时到达服务器
the same time so if we were monitoring
the network we'd see two requests
如果监控网络的话 我们能看到 2 个请求同时到达服务器
heading to the server at the same time
接下来在某个时刻后 服务器会回复它们
and then sometime later the server would
respond to them
这里不足以判断客户端是否收到了第一条请求的回复
so there's actually not enough here to
be able to say whether the client would
不足以判断第一条请求是否被处理
receive would process the first request
也不足以判断服务器是以何种方式处理的它们
first which order there's not enough
here to tell which order the server
也不足以判断服务器是以何种方式处理的它们
processes them in and of course if it
当然了，如果它先处理这个请求
processes this request first then that
然后就意味着它会处理这边这条请求 把值设置成 2
means or it processes the right with
value to second and that means that
接下来后续的读将看到 2
subsequent reads have to see two where is
如果 server 先处理这条请求
it the server happened to process this
然后再处理这条请求
request first and this one's second that
这意味着最终的结果是 1
means the resulting value better be one
然后这两条读请求就会看到 1
and these these two requests and see one
提出这个问题的目的是想说明
so I'm just putting this up to sort
即使是在一个非常简单的系统里也会存在模棱两可的结果
of illustrate that even in a simple
system there's ambiguity you can't
你没办法判断出服务器到底会先处理哪条请求
necessarily tell from trace of what went
也无法判断哪条回复会被先发出去
into the server or what should come out
你能做到的只是判断
all of you can tell is that some set of
在可能的执行上 产生的结果是一致还是不一致的
results is consistent or not consistent
with a possible execution so certainly
所以我们肯定能看到有一些完全错误的结果
there's some completely wrong results we
can see go by it you know if client 3
如果客户端 C3 看到了 2
sees a 2 then client 4 I bet had better
客户端 C4 最好也要能看到 2
see a two also because our model is
因为我们的模型保证第二次写之后是没有问题的
well after the second write you know
客户端 C3 能看到 2 意味着这条请求一定是第 2 次执行
client three sees it two that means
this write must have been second and it
最好是这样 当客户端 C4 能读取到 2 时
still had better be it still has to have
它也必须是第二次写入
been the second write when client 4 goes 2
希望这些东西足够直白
to read the data so hopefully all this is
希望这些东西足够简单 且如预期那样
just completely straightforward and just
因为它就是强一致性的直观模型
as expected because it's it's supposed
to be the intuitive model of strong
ok 这有什么问题呢？
consistency ok and so the problem with
问题在于单个服务器的容错能力很差
this of course is that a single server
has poor fault tolerance right if it
如果它 crash 了 或是磁盘坏了
crashes or it's disk dies or something
那就什么东西都留不下来了
we're left with nothing and so in the
所以在现实世界中的分布式系统
real world of distributed systems we
我们实际上都会构建一个复制系统
actually build replicated systems so and
但是 当我们有了第二份数据副本时
that's where all the problems start
leaking in is when we have a second
这成为了所有问题的发源地
copy data so here is what must be
这里有一个最糟糕的副本设计方案
close to the worst replication design
我写这个是为了警告你
and I'm doing this to warn you of the
这个问题在 GFS 中你也会发现
problems that we will then be looking
好 这里应该写 bad replication design
for in GFS all right so here's a bad
假设现在我们有 2 台 server
replication design we're gonna have two
每台都有一份完整的数据副本
servers now each with a complete copy of
然后在磁盘上 他们都有这样一个 key-value 表格
the data and so on disks that are both
gonna have this this table of keys and
直观上 当然了 我们希望让这两张表完全一致
values the intuition of course is that
we want to keep these tables we hope to
直观上 当然了 我们希望让这两张表完全一致
keep these tables identical so that if
所以 如果其中一台 server 失败了
one server fails we can read or write
我们可以读写另一台服务器
from the other server and so that means
这意味着 每一个写操作都必须在所有的 server 处理
that somehow every write must be
processed by both servers and reads have
另外 read 只能在单台 server 处理 否则就无法容错了
to be able to be processed by a single
server otherwise it's not fault tolerant
因为 如果 read 必须同时和 2 台服务器打交道
all right if reads have to consult both
就无法在失去其中一台 server 的情况下幸免
and we can't survive the loss of one of
所以问题就来了
the servers okay so the problem is gonna
假设客户端 C1 和 C2 同时想执行这些写操作
come up well I suppose we have client 1
and client 2 and they both want to do
其中一个写 1 另一个写 2
these write say one of them gonna write
one and the other is going to write two
所以客户端 C1 需要将请求 Wx1 发送给两台服务器
so client 1 is gonna launch it's write
因为我们就是想更新这 2 台 server
x1 to both because we want to update both
客户端 C2 将请求 Wx2 发给这 2 台 server
of them and clent 2 is gonna launch it's
所以这里就导致出错了
write X so what's gonna go wrong here
(提问) 是的 我们没有做任何事情来保障
yeah yeah we haven't done anything here
2 台 server 以相同的顺序处理这 2 个请求
to ensure that the two servers process
the two requests in the same order right
这个设计真的不怎么样
that's a bad design
如果 S1 先处理 C1 的请求
so if server 1 processes client ones
处理结束后这里这个值变成 1
request first it'll end up it'll start
with a value of 1 and then it'll see
接下来 C2 请求过来 覆盖了这个值变成了 2
client twos request and overwrite that
如果 S2 在接收网络报文的时候
with 2 if server 2 just happens to
刚好是不同的顺序 先收到 C2 的请求先把值设置成 2
receive the packets over the network in
a different order it's going to execute
刚好是不同的顺序 先收到 C2 的请求先把值设置成 2
client 2's requests and set the value to
然后收到 C1 的请求 把值设置成了 1
2 and then then it will see client ones
request set the value to 1 and now what
那么现在 后来的客户端读取的话
a client a later reading client sees you
你应该很清楚 如果碰巧 C3 请求了这台 server
know if client 3 happens to reach from
this server and client for happens to
而 C4 碰巧访问了另一台 server
reach from the other server then we get
于是我们就陷入了一种可怕的场景
into this terrible situation where
他们读取到的值不同
they're gonna read different values even
尽管我们对正确服务的直观模型表明
though our intuitive model of a correct
在随后的 2 次读他们都产生了相同的值
service says they both subsequent reads
have to yeild the same value and this can
但这种问题仍然以另一种方式被暴露出来
arise in other ways you know suppose we
假设客户端尝试
try to fix this by making the clients
只从 S1 或是 S2 读取来修复这个问题
always read from server one if it's up
and otherwise server two if we do that
如果我们这样做了 然后也发生了这种情况
then if this situation happened and for
过了一会儿 这 2 个客户端都去读这个 server
a while，yeah both everybody reads might
这 2 个客户端或许都能看见值 2
see client might see value two but a
但是 S1 突然宕机了
server one suddenly fails then even
x 读取到的值从 2 变成了 1 尽管没有写操作
though there was no write suddenly the
value for X we'll switch from 2 to 1
因为 S1 宕机了 所有的客户端都会切换到 S2
because if server 1 died it's all the
clients will switch to server 2 not but just
这并不是这种数据产生的离奇变化 它不和任何写操作对应
this mysterious change in the data that
doesn't correspond to any write which is
这种事情不会在这种简单的服务模型中发生
also totally not something that could
have happened in this service simple
这种事情不会在这种简单的服务模型中发生
server model all right so of course this
当然了 这个问题可以被修复
can be fixed the fix requires more
修复它需要 server 之间进行更多的通信
communication usually between the
某些地方也会变得更加复杂
servers or somewhere more complexity and
因为想获得强一致性 不可避免的需要更多开销
because of the cost of inevitable cost
to the complexity to get strong
有大量的解决方案可以获得更好的一致性
consistency there's a whole range of
different solutions to get better
也有大量解决方案可以获得让人感觉还能接受的一致性
consistency and a whole range of what
people feel is an acceptable level of
也有大量解决方案可以获得让人感觉还能接受的一致性
consistency in an acceptable sort of a
就算出现一些小瑕疵也还能接受
set of anomalous behaviors that might be
好 关于这个灾难性的模型 还有什么问题吗？
revealed all right any questions about
this disastrous model here
okay 这些就是关于 GFS 的讨论
okay that's what you're talking about
一些关于实现 GFS 的思考 GFS 怎么修复这些问题
GFS a lot of thought about doing GFS was
一些关于实现 GFS 的思考  GFS 怎么修复这些问题
doing is fixing this they had better but
他们做的挺好 但是还不够完美
not perfect behavior okay so where GFS
GFS 是在 2003 年提出的 已经过去相当长一段时间
came from in 2003 quite a while ago
那时候 web 发展到相当规模了 人们也在建立大型网站
actually at that time the the web you
know was certainly starting to be a very
那时候 web 发展到相当规模了 人们也在建立大型网站
big deal and people were building big
此外 分布式系统领域也有了几十年的研究
websites in addition there had been
decades of research into distributed
人们知道至少在学术领域
systems and people sort of knew at least
如何构建各种类型的 高度并行化的且具备容错的系统
at the academic level how to build all
kinds of highly parallel fault tolerant
但是学术上的点子 很少有能应用在工业领域
whatever systems but there been very
little use of academic ideas in industry
但从这篇论文发表之后
but starting at around the time this
像 Google 这样的大型网站才开始真正建立严格意义上分布式系统
paper was published big websites like
Google started to actually build serious
这件事让人热血沸腾 其中就包括我
distributed systems and it was like very
exciting for people like me who were on
作为学术界的一份子
academic side of this to see see real
我切实体会到了所有想法在工业界得以实现
uses of these ideas where Google was
在 Google, 有海量的数据
coming from was you know they had some
这些数据多到单个磁盘远远无法存储
vast vast data sets far larger than
could be stored in a single disk like an
就比如说整个互联网抓取的网页副本
entire crawl copy of the web or a little
或者在这篇文章后边一点有个巨大的 YouTube 视频
bit after this paper they had giant
他们就会有一份比如中间文件的东西 用来建立索引用于搜索
YouTube videos they had things like the
intermedia files for building a search
他们就会有一份比如中间文件的东西 用来建立索引用于搜索
index
他们的 web 服务器显然会有大量的日志文件
they also apparently kept enormous log
files from all their web servers so they
以便用作未来分析
could later analyze them so they had
他们有大量的数据集 并且使用大量的磁盘来存储他们
some big big data sets they used both to
store them and many many disks to store
借助 MapReduce 这样的工具可以快速的处理这些数据
them and they needed to be able to
process them quickly with things like
因此他们需要能高度并行化的访问海量数据
MapReduce so they needed high speed
parallel access to these vast amounts of
okay 所以他们的目标是
data okay so what they were looking for
这个存储系统需要 大容量 速度快
one goal was just that the thing be big
他们还需要一个文件系统 从某种意义上来说
and fast they also wanted a file system
这个文件系统必须是 Global 的（覆盖在整个数据中心上）
that was sort of global in the sense
从某种意义上来说 各种不同的应用程序都能从中读取数据
that many different applications could
有一种建立大型存储系统的方法
get at it one way to build a big storage
假设你有一些特殊的应用程序或是采集程序
system is to you know you have some
particular application or mining you
你可以编写一个专用的存储系统 专门适应这些特别的应用程序
build storage sort of dedicated and
tailored to that application and if
如果你隔壁办公室的人也需要用到大型存储
somebody else in the next office needs
他们就得自己去编写自己的存储系统 而无法复用你的程序
big storage well they can build their
own thing
你要是有一个通用的 Global 且可利用的存储系统
right but if you have a universal server
你要是有一个通用的 Global 且可重用的存储系统
kind of global reusable storage system
这意味着 如果我存储大量从 web 中抓取的数据
and that means that if I store a huge
amount of data set you know I'm crawling
并且你也想查看我抓取的 web 页
the web and you want to look at my
并且你也想看我抓取的 web 页
crawled web web pages because we're all
因为我们都在相同的沙盒中折腾
using we're all playing in the same
且使用了相同的存储系统
sandbox we're all using the same storage
只要访问控制允许的话 你就可以读取我存的文件
system you can just read my files you
know maybe access controls permitting so
所以就有了构建文件系统的想法
the idea was to build a sort of file
任何在 Google 的人 都可以给任何文件命名或是读取它
system where anybody you know anybody
inside Google could name and read any of
目的就是为了共享
the files to allow sharing in order to
为了能得到大容量 速度快的特性
get a in order to get bigness and
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
他们需要把数据进行分割
fastness they need to split the data
每个文件都将自动地被 GFS 分割到许多 server 上
through every file will be automatically
split by GFS over many servers so that
只要有许多客户端大量读取文件 这样读写操作将会自动变快（注：并行化读写）
writes and reads would just
automatically be fast as long as you
只要有许多客户端大量读取文件 这样读写操作将会自动变快（注：并行化读写）
were reading from lots and lots of
reading a file from lots of clients you
你就能获得更高的呑吐量
get higher aggregate throughput and also
而且能够让单个文件比单个磁盘还要大
be able to for a single file be able to
have single files that were bigger than
因为我们构建的东西在数百台服务器之上
any single disk because we're building
something out of hundreds of servers we
所以我们希望这些服务器能够自动的从错误中恢复
want automatic failure recovery we
如果数百台机器中 每时每刻都有机器发生故障
don't want to build a system where every
time one of our hundreds of servers a
这时候你必须得有个人跑到机器去 对着 server 干一些事情
fail some human being has to go to the
machine room and do something with the
比如重启它 或者是迁移数据 或是别的什么也好
server or to get it up and running or
transfers data or something well this
你肯定不愿意用这样的服务 是吧 它都不能自我修复
isn't just fix itself um there were some
还有一些并非是目标 比如 GFS 被设计成只在单数据中心上运行
sort of non goals like one is that GFS
was designed to run in a single data
我们并不会讨论如何把副本放到世界各地
center so we're not talking about
placing replicas all over the world a
单个 GFS 只安装在一个大机房里 只会运行在一个数据中心上
single GFS installation just lived in
one one data center one big machine room
让这样的系统能够在副本彼此相距甚远的情况下工作
so getting this style system to work
with the replicas are far distant from
是一个有价值的目标 但是这还是挺难的
each other is a valuable goal but
这个单数据中心并不是面向客户的服务
difficult so single data centers this is
not a service to customers GFS was for
GFS 是 Google 工程师开发的内部使用的工具
internal use by
applications written by Google engineers
所以他们并不会直接出售这套程序
so it wasn't they weren't directly
但他们可能会出售他们使用的服务
selling this they might be selling
GFS 是内部使用的 他们不会直接出售的
services they used GFS internally but
they weren't selling it directly so it's
GFS 是内部使用的 他们不会直接出售的
just for internal use and it was
而且它是为大型顺序文件读写以多种方式定制的
tailored in a number of ways for big
sequential file reads and writes there's
有一个完全不同的领域 比如为小块数据专门优化的存储系统
a whole nother domain like a system of
storage systems that are optimized for
有一个完全不同的领域 比如为小块数据专门优化的存储系统
small pieces of data like a bank that's
比如银行余额需要有一个数据库
holding bank balances probably wants a
它可以读、写和更新 100 字节存有人们银行余额的记录
database that can read and write and
update you know 100 byte records that
它可以读、写和更新 100 字节存有人们银行余额的记录
hold people's bank balances but GFS is
GFS 可不是这样的系统 它就是为了处理“大文件”
not that system so it's really for big
比如 GB TB 大小的文件
or big is you know terabytes gigabytes
它只处理大文件的顺序访问 而不是随机访问
some big sequential not random access
从某种程度上讲 它有点像批处理的风格
it's also that has a certain batch
它没有花费过多的精力让延迟变的更低
flavor there's not a huge amount of
effort to make access be very low
而是把重点放在巨大的呑吐量上
latency the focus is really on
throughput of big you know multi
比如数兆字节的操作
megabyte operations this paper was
这篇论文 2003 年发表在 SOSP 上
published at SOSP in 2003 the top
一个顶级系统学术会议
system's academic conference yeah usually
通常在这样的会议上 论文标准是需要有很多创新研究
the standard for papers such conferences
they have you know a lot of very novel
这些创新研究在课堂上一定不会有的
research this paper was not necessarily
这篇论文中的点子 在那个时候并不特别新颖
in that class the specific ideas in this
paper none of them are particularly new
像分布式、分片(sharding)、容错这些
at the time and things like distribution
and sharding and fault tolerance were
你能很好的理解并实现它们
you know well understood how to
但是这篇论文描述的系统 是建立在成百上千台机器上的
deliver those but this paper described a
system that was really operating in in
但是这篇论文描述的系统 是建立在成百上千台机器上的
use at a far far larger scale hundreds
of thousands of machines much bigger
数量远远超过了以往学术界建立的系统所使用的机器
than any you know academics ever built
事实上 它被用于工业界 并折射现实世界的经验
the fact that it was used in industry
and reflected real world experience of
比如 对于已经部署的系统  什么不该做 什么该做
like what actually didn't didn't work
for deployed systems that had to work
什么样的开销是最有效率的 这些都是非常有价值的
and had to be cost effective also like
extremely valuable the paper sort of
这篇论文提出了一个相当异端的观点
proposed a fairly heretical view that it
认为存储系统具有弱一致性是可以接受的
was okay for the storage system to have
pretty weak consistency
在那时候 学术界的观念认为存储系统就应该具有良好的行为
we the academic mindset at
that time was the you know the storage
在那时候 学术界的观念认为存储系统就应该具有良好的行为
system really should have good behavior
像这里的这个糟糕的复制系统 它返回了错误的数据
like what's the point of building
systems that sort of return the wrong
像这里的这个糟糕的复制系统 它返回了错误的数据
data like my terrible replication system
它为什么要这样做 而不是构建一个能返回正确数据的系统
like why do that why not build systems
return the right data correct data
它为什么要这样做 而不是构建一个能返回正确数据的系统
instead of incorrect data now with this
在这篇论文里 它确实没有保证返回的正确的数据
paper actually does not guarantee return
它的目的是获取更好的性能
correct data and you know the hope is
that they take advantage of that in
它的目的是获取更好的性能
order to get better performance I'm a
最后一件事 这篇论文里 使用的是单个 master
final thing that was sort of interesting
about this paper is its use of a single
在学术论文里 你可能会有自动容错的副本 用以恢复 master
master in a sort of academic paper you
probably have some fault-tolerant
在学术论文里 你可能会有自动容错的副本 用以恢复 master
replicated automatic failure recovering
或许有许多的 master 进行分工
master perhaps many masters with the
但是在这篇论文里
work split open um but this paper said
它得以侥幸的只使用一个 master 并且能工作的很好
look you know you they can get away with
a single master and it worked fine well
(提问) 很讽刺的是 谁关心 web 页面上投票的数量是否正确呢
cynically you know who's going to notice
on the web that some vote count or
又或是别的什么错误呢
something is wrong or if you do a search
如果你在搜索引擎上执行搜索
on a search engine now you're gonna know
可能会发生 20000 条结果里有一条搜索结果丢失这样的事情
that oh you know like one of 20,000
items is missing from the search results
这些结果的排序可能也不正确
or they're in the wrong order probably
所以在这类系统中 它对错误数据容错能力不需要像银行系统那样高
not so there was just much more
tolerance in these kind of systems than
所以在这类系统中 它对错误数据容错能力不需要像银行系统那样高
there would like in a bank for incorrect
这并不是说所有数据所有的 web 网站都可以是错误的
data it doesn't mean that all data and
websites can be wrong like if you're
比如你收了别人的钱 给人家打广告
charging people for ad impressions you
你最好还是得保证数字的正确性 这不一定就是这样哈
better get the numbers right but this is
另外 GFS 中有一些提供数据的方法 可以在应用程序中进行补偿
not really about that in addition some
of the ways in which GFS could serve up
另外 GFS 中有一些提供数据的方法 可以在应用程序中进行补偿
all data could be compensated for in the
比如论文中介绍的 应用程序应当把数据及其校验和一起使用
applications like where the paper says
you know applications should accompany
比如论文中介绍的 应用程序应当把数据及其校验和一起使用
their data with checksums and clearly
并且要清晰的标记记录的边界
mark record boundaries that's so the
所以应用程序就能从 GFS 中恢复数据
applications can recover from GFS
提供服务可能并不需要强烈保证数据的正确性
serving them maybe not quite the right data
好，所以一般的结构是……就在这篇论文的图 1 里
all right so the general structure and
this is just figure one in the paper so
我们有很多客户端 上百个吧 还有一个 master
we have a bunch of clients hundreds
hundreds of clients we have one master
尽管存在 master 的多个副本
although there might be replicas of the
在这里 master 保存有从文件名到数据存储位置的映射
master the master keeps the mapping from
file names to where to find the data
实际上是有 2 张表
basically although there's really two
然后 还有许多的 chunk server（块服务器）
tables so and then there's a bunch of
chunk servers maybe hundreds of chunk
可能会有上百个 每一个可能都会有一两块磁盘
servers each with perhaps one or two
这里的 master 用来管理命名和追踪 chunk 的位置
disks the separation here's the master
is all about naming and knowing where
chunk server 会存储实际的数据
the chunks are and the chunk servers
store the actual data this is like a
这看起来是设计中最好的地方了
nice aspect of the design that these two
这两个地方完全彼此隔离起来
concerns are almost completely separated
并能使用独立的特性进行独立设计
from each other and can be designed just
separately with separate properties the
master 知道所有的文件 并且能追踪这些 chunk、chunk 标识符
master knows about all the files for
every file the master keeps track of a
master 知道所有的文件 并且能追踪这些 chunk、chunk 标识符
list of chunks chunk identifiers that
chunk 中包含文件的连续片断 每个 chunk 大小是 64MB
contain the successive pieces that file
each chunk is 64 megabytes so if I have
如果我有 1GB 的文件
a you know gigabyte file the master is
master 就会知道这个文件的第 1 个 chunk 保存在这里
gonna know that maybe the first chunk is
第 2 个 chunk 保存在这里
stored here and the second chunk is
第 3 个 chunk 保存在这里
stored here the third chunk is stored
如果我想读取这个文件中的任意一部分
here and if I want to read whatever part
就需要询问 master 这个 chunk 在哪个 server 上
of the file I need to ask the master oh
which server holds that chunk and I go
然后就去找那个 server 读取 chunk 粗略的说就是这样
talk to that server and read the chunk
roughly speaking all right so more
说的细一点 我们需要证明我们所讨论的
precisely we need to turns out for
关于系统如何保持一致性 以及如何处理错误的问题
going to talk about how the system about
the consistency of the system and how it
关于系统如何保持一致性 以及如何处理错误的问题
deals with fault we need to know what
我们需要了解 master 实际存储的是什么这些细节
the master is actually storing in a
little bit more detail so the master data
master data 我们所关心的是它实际存储的 2 个主要 table
it's got two main tables that we care
其中一个是 filename 到 chunk ID(或chunk handle) 数组的映射
about it's got one table that map's file
name to an array of chunk IDs or chunk
这张表是为了告诉你在哪里可以找到数据 或者说这些 chunk 是什么
handles this just tells you where to
find the data or what the what the
这张表是为了告诉你在哪里可以找到数据 或者说这些 chunk 是什么
identifiers are the chunks are so it's
拿着这样一个 chunk id 你还没办法做其它事
not much yet you can do with a chunk
但是 master 碰巧它还有第 2 张表
identifier but the master also happens
to have a a second table that map's
它记录了每个 chunk handle 到一些数据之间的映射
chunk handles each chunk handle to a
bunch of data about that chunk so one is
其中一项是 chunk server 的列表
the list of chunk servers that hold
这些 chunk server 保存数据的副本
replicas of that data each chunk is
每个 chunk 被存储在多个 chunk server 上
stored on more than one chunk server so
所以这里应该写上 chunk server 列表
it's a list of chunk servers every chunk
每一个 chunk 都有一个当前版本号
has a current version number so this
所以 master 还得记住每个 chunk 的版本号
master has a remembers the version
对于 chunk 的所有写操作
number for each chunk all writes for a
都必须在 chunk primary (主 chunk) 上顺序化
chunk have to be sequence of the chunks
这个 primary 是所有副本之一
primary it's one of the replicas so
所以 master 记住了哪个 chunk server 是 primary
master remembers the which chunk server is
primary 只能在规定的某个租约时间里才能担任 primary
the primary and there's also that
primary is only allowed to be primary
primary 只能在规定的某个租约时间里才能担任 primary
for a certain lease time so the master
所以 master 还应该记住这个租约的过期时间
remembers the expiration time of the
这些东西全部存储在 RAM(内存) 中
lease this stuff so far it's all in RAM
如果 master 宕机 这些东西就全部丢失了
and the master so just be gone if the
为了能重启 master 并且不丢失文件系统相关的信息
master crashed so in order that you'd be
able to reboot the master and not forget
为了能重启 master 并且不丢失文件系统相关的信息
everything about the file system the
master 会把这些数据存储到磁盘上 和在内存里一样
master actually stores all of this data
on disk as well as in memory so reads
读数据的时候 只从内存里读
just come from memory but writes to at
least the parts of this data that had to
但是写数据 至少这部分数据 必须也要写入磁盘
be reflected on this writes have to go
所以这种管理方式 要求所有的 master 在磁盘上都有一个 log
to the disk so and the way it actually
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
所以这种管理方式 要求所有的 master 在磁盘上都有一个 log
managed that is that there's all
the master has a log on disk and every
任何时候有数据变更 就会在磁盘上的日志追加一个条目 并定期创建 checkpoint
time it changes the data it appends an
entry to the log on disk and checkpoint
有些东西它必须要保存到磁盘上 有些不用 我猜测是这样
so some of this stuff actually needs to
be on disk and some doesn't it turns out
有些东西它必须要保存到磁盘上 有些不用 我猜测是这样
I'm guessing a little bit here but
当然了 chunk handle 数组那肯定要保存到磁盘上
certainly the array of chunk handles has
所以这里我里写一个 NV(non-valatile, 非易失)
to be on disk and so I'm gonna write nv
here for non-volatile meaning it it's
表示它会被反射到磁盘上
got to be reflected on disk the list of
chunk server 列表不会保存到磁盘上
chunk servers it turns out doesn't
因为 master 重启后会和所有 chunk server 通信
because the master if it reboots talks
并询问它们保存了哪些 chunk
to all the chunk servers and ask them
what chunks they have so this is I
所以我觉得它不用写入磁盘
imagine not written to disk the version
版本号要不要写入磁盘 这得要求了解系统如何工作
number any guesses written to disk not
written to disk requires knowing how the
不过我偏向于它会写入磁盘（nv）
system works I'm gonna vote written to
disk non-volatile we can argue about
稍后我们讨论系统如何工作的时候再来争论这个问题
that later when we talk about how system
primary 标识不用写入到磁盘 所以应该是 volatile
works identity the primary it turns out
not almost certainly not written to disk
因为 master 在重启后就会忘记谁是 primary
so volatile and the reason is the master
is um reboots and forgets therefore
因为 master 在重启后就会忘记谁是 primary
since it's volatile forgets who the
对于一个 chunk 来说 只要简单的等待 60 秒 等待租约过期
primary is for a chunk it can simply
wait for the 60-second lease expiration time
然后它便知道对于这个 chunk 来说确实没有 primary 在工作
and then it knows that absolutely no
primary will be functioning for this
这时候它可以安全的指定一个不同的 primary
chunk and then it can designate a
different primary safely and similarly
类似的 租约过期时间也是 volatile
the lease expiration stuff is volatile
任何时候文件达到 64MB 边界时需要创建一个新 chunk
so that means that whenever a file is
又或是新的 primary 被指派导致版本号发生改变时
extended with a new chunk growth to the
next 64 megabyte boundary or the version
master 都必须首先追加一点记录到日志中
number changes because the new primary
is designated that means that the master
master 都必须首先追加一点记录到日志中
has to first append a little record to
内容大概是 我刚添加了个 chunk 到这个文件里
his log basically saying oh I just added
a such-and-such a chunk to this file or
或者是 我刚修改一下版本号
I just changed the version number so
所以每次我修改这些东西都需要写入磁盘
every time I change is one of those that
needs to writes disk so this
这篇论文并没的讨论这么多细节
is paper doesn't talk about this
但是你得知道 master 修改这些东西总会存在一些速率限制
much but you know there's limits the
rate at which the master can change
因为你每秒能写磁盘的次数就那么多
things because you can only write your
disk however many times per second and
使用日志而不是数据库的原因是
the reason for using a log rather than a
你应该了解过 b-tree 或是 hash 表
database you know some sort of b-tree or
hash table on disk is that you can
使用日志是因为追加日志非常高效
append a log very efficiently because
你有一堆最近的日志记录需要被添加
you only need you can take a bunch of
recent log records they need to be added
在一次磁盘旋转后 一次把他们写入磁盘上某个位置
and sort of write them all on a single
write after a single rotation to
在一次磁盘旋转后 一次把他们写入磁盘上某个位置
whatever the point in the disks that
这个位置包含了日志文件的结尾(EOF)
contains the end of the log file whereas
然而 如果使用 b-tree 来表达这些数据的话
if it were a sort of b-tree reflecting
the real structure of this data then you
那就还得去磁盘上寻找一个随机位置写入一点数据
would have to seek to a random place in
the disk and do a little write so the
所以日志会让这种写操作稍稍快一些
log makes a little bit faster to write
为了把这些操作反射到磁盘上
there to reflect operations on to the
然而如果 master 宕机并且必须重建它的状态
disk however if the master crashes and
has to reconstruct its state you
你可能并不想从日志文件从头开始读取重建
wouldn't want to have to reread its log
file back starting from the beginning of
因为 server 第一次安装启动的时间开始距今可能有数年
time from when the server was first
installed you know a few years ago so in
所以 master 有时候会额外的创建一份它完整状态的快照到磁盘
addition the master sometimes
checkpoints its complete state to disk
这可能会花费几十秒 比如一分钟的时间
which takes some amount of time seconds
maybe a minute or something and then
当它重启的时候 它只要回到最近的 checkpoint 的位置
when it restarts what it does is goes
back to the most recent checkpoint and
然后重演从 checkpoint 之后的日志就行了
plays just the portion of a log that
sort of starting at the point in time
然后重演从 checkpoint 之后的日志就行了
when that check one is created any
关于 master 数据大家还有啥疑问没 okay
questions about the master data okay
所以基于以上 我打算列出这些在读和写中的步骤
so with that in mind I'm going to lay
out the steps in the read and the steps in
所以基于以上 我打算列出这些在读和写中的步骤
the write
所有的步骤我会写在这里 然后和你们一起讨论
where all this is heading is that I then
want to discuss you know for each
对于每一个失败 我可以思考在失败之后为什么系统要这样做
failure I can think of why does the
system or does the system act directly
但是在做这件事前 我们需要理解这些数据和数据中的操作
after that failure um but in order to do
that we need to understand the data and
但是在做这件事前 我们需要理解这些数据和数据中的操作
operations in the data okay so if
okay 这里是 read 第一步是客户端
there's a read the first step is that
read 意思是应用程序知道有一个文件名
the client and what a read means that
the application has a file name in mind
read 意思是应用程序知道有一个文件名
and an offset in the file that it wants
以及一个应用程序想从某个位置读取的偏移量
to read some data from so it sends the
所以应用程序会把文件名和偏移发送给 master
file name and the offset to the master
master 从文件表里查询文件名
and the master looks up the file name in
你知道每个 chunk 大小是 64MB
its file table and then you know each
chunk is 64 megabytes who can use the
它可以利用偏移量除以 64MB 来查找是哪个 chunk
offset divided by 64 megabytes to find
然后再从 chunk 表里找到 chunk server 列表
which chunk and then it looks up that
chunk in its chunk table finds the list
然后再从 chunk 表里找到 chunk server 列表
of chunk servers that have replicas of
再把包含这些数据的副本的 chunk server 列表返回给客户端
that data and returns that list to the
所以第一步是把文件名和偏移量发给 master
client so the first step is so you know
the file name and the offset to master
然后 master 发送 chunk handle(记作 H) 和 server 列表（给客户端)
and the master sends the chunk handle
let's say H and the list of servers so
现在我有一些选择 我可以查询这个 server 列表中的任意一个
now we have some choice we can ask any
one of these servers pick one that's and
论文里说客户端会尝试猜测
the paper says that clients try to guess
网络上（也可能是一个机架上）哪个 server 距离它最近
which server is closest to them in the
network maybe in the same rack and send
然后发送读请求到那个副本上
the read request to that to that replica
客户端实际上会缓存这些结果
the client actually caches
如果它尝试再次读取这个 chunk 的话
caches this result so that if it reads
that chunk again and indeed the client
客户端可能从返回的 chunk 中读取 1MB 或是 64KB 的片段
might read a given chunk in you know one
megabyte pieces or 64 kilobyte pieces or
客户端可能最终会读取同一个 chunk 中不同的位置连续的区域多次
something so client may end up reading the
same chunk different points successive
客户端可能最终会读取同一个 chunk 中不同的位置连续的区域多次
regions of a chunk many times and so
所以需要缓存给定的 chunk 所对应的是哪个 server
caches which server to talk to you for
对于相同的信息 它就不用一遍又一遍的去访问 master
giving chunks so it doesn't have to keep
beating on the master asking the master
对于相同的信息 它就不用一遍又一遍的去访问 master
for the same information over and over
客户端和 chunk server 之一进行通信
now the client talks to one of the chunk
发送一个 chunk handle 以及一个偏移
servers tells us a chunk handle and offset
chunk server 存储这些 chunk
and the chunk servers store these chunks
每个 chunk 在硬盘上都是一个独立的 Linux 文件
each chunk in a separate Linux file on
位于普通的 Linux 文件系统里
their hard drive in a ordinary Linux
假定这些 chunk 文件就是通过 handle 来命名
file system and presumably the chunk
files are just named by the handle so
所以 chunk server 需要做的就是使用正确的名字找到这个文件
all the chunk server has to do is go
find the file with the right name you
找到整个 chunk 后 读取客户端期望的字节范围数据
know I'll give it that
entire chunk and then just read the
找到整个 chunk 后 读取客户端期望的字节范围数据
desired range of bytes out of that file
最后返回数据给客户端
and return the data to the client I hate
不要问我怎么执行读操作 我讨厌这样的问题
question about how reads operate can I
(提问) 我是否能再重复讲一遍 step 1
repeat number one the step one is the
step 1 表示应用程序想读取
application wants to read it a
某个特定的文件的某个特定的偏移上的数据
particular file at a particular offset
within the file a particular range of
某个特定范围里 比如 1000 到 2000 字节范围的数据
bytes in the files and one thousand to
two thousand and so it just sends a name
所以它只要发送一个文件名和要读取的字节范围给 master
of the file and the beginning of the
byte range to the master and then the
然后 master 从文件表里查询这个文件名
master looks a file name and it's file
找到包含这个字节范围的 chunk
table to find the chunk that contains
that byte range for that file so good
(提问)
我不知道详细的细节
so I don't know the exact details my
我印象中是如果应用程序想读取超过 64MB 的数据
impression is that the if the
application wants to read more than 64
或者仅仅只是想读取 2 个字节数据但是却跨越了 chunk 的边界
megabytes or even just two bytes but
spanning a chunk boundary that the
应用程序所链接的依赖库
library so the applications linked with
就是那个底层发送数据到不同 server 的依赖库
a library that sends our pcs to the
various servers and that library would
它将会注意到这个读请求跨越了一个 chunk 边界
notice that the reads spanned a chunk
于是它会把这条读请求分割成 2 个读请求发送到 master
boundary and break it into two separate
reads and maybe talk to the master I
意思是可能你只和 master 通信 1 次但你会得到 2 条结果
mean it may be that you could talk to
the master once and get two results or
但是从逻辑上讲 请求 master 2 次
something but logically at least it two
接下来就会请求 2 个不同的 chunk server
requests to the master and then requests
to two different chunk servers yes well
至少在一开始对于给定的文件 客户端不知道需要哪个 chunk
at least initially the client doesn't
know for a given file
至少在一开始对于给定的文件 客户端不知道需要哪个 chunk
what chunks need what chunks well it can
是的，客户端能够计算出来它需要第 17 个 chunk
calculate it needs the seventeenth chunk
但是它需要知道是哪个 chunk server 持有这个文件的第 17 个 chunk
but but then it needs to know what chunk
server holds the seventeenth chunk of
客户端需要和 master 通信才能知道这个信息
that file and for that it certainly
needs for that it needs to talk to the
(提问)
master okay so all right did I'm not
我不保证到底是哪种方式来判断它是文件件第 17 个 chunk
going to make a strong claim about which
of them decides that it was the
我不保证到底是哪种方式来判断它是文件件第 17 个 chunk
seventeenth chunk in the file but it's
但是 master 它能找到第 17 个 chunk 的 handler 标识符
the master that finds the identifier of
the handle of the seventeenth chunk in
它只要查一下它的表就能知道哪个哪个 chunk server 持有这个 chunk
the file looks that up in its table and
figures out which chunk servers hold
它只要查一下它的表就能知道哪个哪个 chunk server 持有这个 chunk
that chunk yes
(提问) 你的意思是如果客户端请求的字节范围跨越了 chunk 边界
how does that or you mean if the if the
你的意思是如果客户端请求的字节范围跨越了 chunk 边界
client asks for a range of bytes that
spans a chunk boundary yeah so the the
嗯，客户端本身链接了 GFS 的 lib 库
well you know the client will ask that
well the clients linked with this
嗯，客户端本身链接了 GFS 的 lib 库
library is a GFS library that noticed
lib 库能注意到并知道如何把读请求分割
how to take read requests apart and put
然后把它们的返回结果合并起来
them back together and so that library
所以 lib 会和 master 进行通信
would talk to the master and the master
master 将会告诉他
would tell it well well you know chunk
好的好的 chunk 7 号在这个 server 上
seven is on this server and chunk eight
chunk 8 在那个 server 上
is on that server and then why the
lib 就能对 chunk server 说
library would just be able to say oh you
oh 我要 chunk 7 号的最后 2 个字节
know I need the last couple bytes of
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
chunk 8 号的头 2 个字节
chunk seven and the first couple bytes
接下来把请求到的数据一起放到 buffer 里返回给应用层
of chunk eight and then would fetch
those put them together in a buffer and
接下来把请求到的数据一起放到 buffer 里返回给应用层
return them to the calling application
master 会告诉它关于 chunk 的信息
well the master tells it about chunks
lib 能够在给定的 chunk 中找到应用程序想要的数据
and the library kind of figures out
where it should look in a given chunk to
lib 能够在给定的 chunk 中找到应用程序想要的数据
find the data of the application wanted
应用程序只要想好文件名 以及整个文件中的偏移位置
the application only thinks in terms of
file names and sort of just offsets in
应用程序只要想好文件名 以及整个文件中的偏移位置
the entire file in the library and the
master 就能根据这些信息返回 chunk 信息
master conspire to turn that into chunks
(提问)
yeah
sorry 我得离你近一点 你再讲一遍
sorry let me get closer here you say
所以问题是 从哪个 chunk server 读取数据很重要吗
again so the question is does it matter
which chunk server you read from so you
哈哈 是或不是都行 从概念上讲他们都是副本
know yes and no notionally they're all
supposed to be replicas in fact as you
事实上你可能已经注意到了 之前我们讨论过他们并不都是
may have noticed or as we'll talk about
你知道 他们并不完全相同
they're not you know they're not
necessarily identical and applications
应用程序应该是能够容忍这种情况
are supposed to be able to tolerate this
但是事实上是依赖于你读取的 chunk server 副本
but the fact is that you make a slightly
你得到的数据会有稍稍不同
different data depending on which
所以论文上说客户端会尝试
replicas you read yeah so the paper says
从相同的机架上或是从同一个交换机后的 server 读取数据
that clients try to read from the chunk
server that's in the same rack or on the
从相同的机架上或是从同一个交换机后的 server 读取数据
same switch or something all right so
好的 读取数据就是这些
that's reads
写的话会更加复杂一点 但是挺有趣
the writes are more complex and
应用程序对于写的接口是类似的
interesting now the application
interface for writes is pretty similar
有一些函数调用 一些可调用的库可以请求 gfs
there's just some call some library you
call to make you make to the gfs client
客户端 lib 库请求会说
library saying look here's a file name
看 这儿有个文件名以及一段我想写的字节数据
and a range of bytes I'd like to write
这个 buffer 里的数据 我请求你能写入
and the buffer of data that I'd like you
to write to that that range actually let
稍稍往后退一步 我只是想讨论记录追加 所以我打算
me let me backpedal I only want to talk
about record appends and so I'm going to
称赞一下这种客户端接口
praise this the client interface as the
客户端发起 lib 库调用会说
client makes a library call that says
这有个文件名 我想把这个 buffer 里的字节数据追加到文件里
here's a file name and I'd like to
append this buffer of bytes to the file
我说的这个就是论文里讨论的记录追加
I said this is the record appends that
the paper talks about so again the
客户端会发送 “我想追加数据“ 这样的请求到 master
client asks the master look I want to
append sends a master requesting what I
请求内容是 我要给这个名字的文件追加数据
would like to append this named file
请告诉我这个文件最后一个 chunk 在哪里
please tell me where to look for the
last chunk in the file because the
如果有很多客户端向相同的文件里追加
client may not know how long the file is
客户端可能就不知道文件有多长
if lots of clients are appending the
因为我们有一些大文件
same file because we have some big file
比如许多不同客户端的日志
this logging stuff from a lot of
different clients may be you know
client不知道文件有多长
no client will necessarily know how long
因此也不知道偏移量，或是应该附加到哪个 chunk 中
the file is and therefore which offset
or which chunk it should be appending to
你可以问master，请告诉我
so you can ask the master please tell me
包含当前该文件最后一个 chunk 的服务器的信息
about the the server's that hold the
very last chunk
包含当前该文件最后一个 chunk 的服务器的信息
current chunk in this file
很不幸的是 现在是写操作
so unfortunately now the writing
如果你在读取，你可以从任何最新副本中读取内容
if you're reading you can read from any up-to-date replica
对于写的情况，需要有一个primary
for writing though there needs
此时文件上的 primary 可能已经由master指定 也可能没有
to be a primary so at this point on the
file may or may not have a primary
此时文件上的 primary 可能已经由master指定 也可能没有
already designated by the master
所以我们需要考虑这个情况
so we need to consider the case of if there's
如果还没有primary
no primary already and all the master
并且 master 知道不存在 primary
knows well there's no primary so
第一种情况是没有primary
so one case is no primary
在这种情况下，master 服务器需要
in that case the master needs to find
找出具有最新 chunk 副本的 chunk 服务器集合
out the set of chunk servers that have
the most up-to-date copy of the chunk
因为，如果你的系统已经运行了很长时间
because know if you've been running the
system for a long time due to failures
由于故障或其他原因
or whatever there may be chunk servers
导致有的 chunk 服务器存在旧的副本
out there that have old copies of the
比如昨天或上周的我保持的最新的副本
chunk from you know yesterday or last
week that I've been kept up to kept up
因为该服务器可能已挂了两天 而没有更新
to date because maybe that server was
dead for a couple days and wasn't
因为该服务器可能已挂了两天 而没有更新
receiving updates so there's you need to
因此，你需要能够分辨出 新旧副本之间的区别
be able to tell the difference between
up-to-date copies of the chunk and non up-to-date
所以第一步是要找到 找到最新的
so the first step is to find
you know find up-to-date this is all
这一切都发生在master
happening in the master because the
因为client请求master
client has asked the master told the
告诉master我要追加此文件
master look I want up end of this file
请告诉我要与哪些块服务器对话
please tell me what chunk service to talk to
所以master服务器一部分
so a part of the master trying
试图弄清楚client端
to figure out what chunk servers the
应该与哪些服务器通信
client should talk to you
所以当我们最终找到最新的副本时
so when we finally find up-to-date
up-to-date 的意思是
replicas and what up-to-date means is a
一个副本中的 chunk 版本等于 master 服务器知道的最新版本号
replica whose version of the chunk is
equal to the version number that the
一个副本中的 chunk 版本等于 master 服务器知道的最新版本号
master knows is the most up-to-date version number
因为这些版本号是 master 服务器分发的
it's the master that
hands out these version numbers
所以 master 记得它们，oh
the master remembers that oh for this
对于这个特定的 chunk
particular chunk you know the chunk
仅当 chunk 服务器的版本号为 17 时它才是最新的
server is only up to date if it has
version number 17 and this is why it has
这就是为什么它必须是非易失性的 需要存储在磁盘上的原因
to be non-volatile stored on disk
如果版本号在崩溃中丢失
because if if it was lost in a crash and
并且 chunk 服务器持有过时 chunk 副本
there were chunk servers holding stale
copies of chunks the master wouldn't be
master 就无法区分
able to distinguish between chunk
这个 chunk sever 上的 chunk 副本是上周的还是最新的
servers holding stale copies of a chunk
from last week and a chunk server that
这个 chunk sever 上的 chunk 副本是上周的还是最新的
holds the copy of the chunk that was
up-to-date as of the crash that's why
这就是为什么 master 服务器需要把版本号记在磁盘上的的原因
the master remembers the version number on disk
(提问)
yeah
如果你正在与所有 chunk 服务器通信
if you knew you were talking to all the
okay 结论是如果 master 重启
chunk servers okay so the observation is
the master has to talk to the chunk
master 服务器无论如何都要与 chunk 服务器进行通信
servers anyway if it reboots in order to
来确定哪个 chunk 服务器持有哪个 chunk
find which chunk server holds which chunk
因为 master 不记得那些信息了
because the master doesn't
你可能会想 你只要找到 version 最大的那个就行
remember that so you might think that
you could just take the maximum you
你只需和 chunk 服务器通信 找出他们拥有哪些 chunk 和版本
could just talk to the chunk servers
find out what trunks and versions they
从所有响应中找到 version 最大值
hold and take the maximum for a given
chunk overall the responding chunk
如果所有持有 chunk 的 chunk 服务器都响应
servers and that would work if all the
这种做法没有问题
chunk servers holding a chunk responded
但风险是 master 重启时
but the risk is that at the time the
也许一些 chunk 服务器离线或断开连接
master reboots maybe some of the chunk
servers are offline or disconnected or
或是别的什么原因重新 导致它不响应 master
whatever themselves rebooting and don't respond
导致 master 拿到的都是持有前几周旧副本的 chunk server 的响应
and so all the master gets back
is responses from chunk servers that
导致 master 拿到的都是持有前几周旧副本的 chunk server 的响应
have last week's copies of the block and
而具有最新副本的 chunk 服务器还没完成重启 甚至是离线
the chunk servers that have the current
copy haven't finished rebooting or
而具有最新副本的 chunk 服务器还没完成重启 甚至是离线
offline or something so ok oh yes if
如果服务器上所有的最新版本都失效或丢失的话 答案是 yes
if the server's holding the most recent
copy are permanently dead if you've lost
如果服务器上所有的最新版本都失效或丢失的话 答案是 yes
all copies all of the most recent
version of a chunk then yes
不对
No
okay，问题是，master 知道
okay so the question is the master knows
对于这个 chunk 寻找版本17
that for this chunk is looking for
version 17
假设它找不到这样的 chunk 服务器
supposing it finds no chunk server you
你知道 master 会定期与 chunk 服务器进行对话以询问它们
know and it talks to the chunk servers
periodically to sort of ask them what
拥有哪些块 拥有什么版本
chunks do you have what versions you have
假设它没有找到包含版本 17 chunk 服务器
supposing it finds no server with
chunk 17 with version 17 for this this
master 要么先不回复并等待
chunk then the master will either say
well either not respond yet and wait or
要么告诉 client，我无法回答，请稍后再试
it will tell the client look I can't
要么告诉client，我无法回答，请稍后再试
answer that try again later and this
就像建筑物中的电源故障
would come up like there was a power
failure in the building and all the
所有服务器都崩溃了，我们正在缓慢地重新启动
server's crashed and we're slowly rebooting
master 可能先启动完成
the master might come up first
一些 chunk 服务器可能已启动
and you know some fraction of the chunk
其他的在五分钟后才完成启动
servers might be up and other ones would
reboot five minutes from now but
所以必须等待 并且会永远等待
so we have to be prepared to wait and
it will wait forever because you don't want to
因为你不想使用 chunk 的旧版本
use a stale version of that of a chunk
所以 master 需要整合具有最新版本的 chunk 服务器列表
okay so the master needs to assemble the
list of chunk servers that have the most
master 知道磁盘上存储的最新版本
recent version the master knows the most
recent versions stored on disk each
正如你所指出的 每个 chunk 服务器以及每个 chunk
chunk server along with each chunk as
you pointed out also remembers the
也记得它存储的 chunk 的版本号
version number of the chunk that it's stores
当 chunk 服务器向 master 报告说
so that when chunk servers
看，我有这个 chunk
reported into the master saying look I
master 服务器便可以
have this chunk the master can ignore
忽略那些版本与 master 知道的最新版本不匹配的 chunk server
the ones whose version does not match
the version the master knows is the most recent
okay 回到之前的话题 我们 client 想要执行追加
okay so remember we were the
client want to append the master doesn't
但是 master 还没有 primary 它意识到
have a primary it figures out maybe you
你可能需要等待具有该 chunk 最新版本的服务器集合
have to wait for the set of chunk
servers that have the most recent
master 会挑一个 chunk server 出来作为 primary
version of that chunk it picks a primary
所以我要选择其中一个作为 primary
so I'm gonna pick one of them to be the
primary and the others to be secondary servers
将其他作为 secondary（次级服务）
among the replicas set at the most
然后 master 将版本号递增 并将其写入磁盘
recent version the master then
increments the version number and writes that to
这样在崩溃时也不会丢失（版本号）
disk so it doesn't forget it the crashes
接下来请求 primary 和 secondary
and then it sends the primary and
通知它们都是什么身份
secondaries and that's each of them a
每个 chunk server 都能收到一条消息：找到这个 chunk
message saying look for this chunk
这是 primary，这是 secondary
here's the primary here's the
收件人可能是其中之一
secondaries you know recipient maybe one
这个新版本号
of them and here's the new version
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
然后它会把这个信息以及版本号告诉 primary 和 secondary
number so then it tells primary
secondaries this information plus the
primary 节点和 secondary 节点都将版本号写入磁盘
version number the primaries and secondaries
all write the version number to disk
所以它们不会丢失这个信息
so they don't forget because you know
如果因为电源故障或其他原因
if there's a power failure or whatever
等它们重启后必须拿着这个版本号向 master 报告
they have to report in to the master with the
actual version number they hold yes
问题很棒
that's a great question
我不知道答案 不过论文中有提示
so I don't know there's hints in the
关于你问的这点 其实之前我犯了点小错误
paper that I'm slightly wrong about this
我觉得你的问题已经做了解释
so the paper says I think your question
was explaining something to me about the
论文里说 如果 master 重启并与 chunk server 进行通信
paper the paper says if the master
reboots and talks to chunk servers and
并且其中一个 chunk server 重启时报告的版本号
one of the chunk servers reboot reports
高于 master 记住的版本号
a version number that's higher than the
version number the master remembers the
master 会假设它在分配新 primary 时发生了某些错误
master assumes that there was a failure
while it was assigning a new primary and
于是它会使用这个更高的版本号（来自这个 chunk server）作为当前版本号
adopts the new the higher version number
that it heard from a chunk server
为什么会有这么诡异的错误？
so it must be the case that in order to handle
我觉得是 master 在通知 primary 之后才做的持久化
a master crash at this point that
the master writes its own version number to
但碰巧 在把版本号写入磁盘之前 master 崩了
disk after telling the primaries there's
所以这里是有点问题的
a bit of a problem here though because
(提问) 是否有 ACK ?
if the was that is there an ACK
master 服务器可能会告知 primary 和 backup
all right so maybe the master tells the
primaries and backups that they're...
是告知 primary 和 secondary
primaries and secondaries if there a
如果有 primary secondary 就通知它新版本号
primary secondary tells him the new
然后等待 ACK 再写入磁盘 或是其它不满足条件的操作
version number waits for the AK and then
writes to disk or something unsatisfying about this
我认为这行不通
I don't believe that works
因为存在这种可能性
because of the possibility that the
master 服务器重启时 具有最新版本号的 chunk server 可能是离线的
chunk servers with the most recent
version numbers being offline at the
master 服务器重启时 具有最新版本号的 chunk server 可能是离线的
time the master reboots we wouldn't want
我们不希望 master 不知道当前版本号
the master the master doesn't know the
current version number it'll just accept
因为它收到的所谓的最高的版本号 可能是个旧版本号
whatever highest version number here
which could be an old version number
这个领域我知道的不多
alright so this is a an area of my
我不太清楚 master 是否是先更新其自己的版本号
ignorance I don't really understand
whether the master update system version
再告诉 primary 和 secondary 又或是其他方式
number on this first and then tells the
primary secondary or the other way around
我不确定它采用哪种方式
and I'm not sure it works either
但无论如何 总有某种方式
way okay but in any case one way or another
master 更新其版本号 并告诉 primary secondary
the master update its version
number tells the primary secondary look
看看你的 primaries 和 secondaries，这儿还有个最新版本号
your primaries and secondaries here's a
new version number and so now we have a
现在我们有了一个可以接受写入的 primary
primary which is able to accept writes
primary 的工作是接收客户端的请求
alright that's what the primaries job
is to take writes from clients and
将这些写入进行组织成一定顺序 然后应用于各个 chunk servers
organize applying those writes to the
various chunk servers and you know the
版本号的目的是使 master 能找到哪些 server 具有最新的 chunk
reason for the version number stuff is
so that the master will recognize the
版本号的目的是使 master 能找到哪些 server 具有最新的 chunk
which servers have this new you know the
master 授予某些 chunk server 成为 primary 的能力
master hands out the ability to be
primary for some chunk server we want to
我们希望能够辨认出 如果主机崩溃
be able to recognize if the master
crashes you know that it was that was
只有那个 primary 和 secondaries
the primary that only that primary and
it secondaries which were actually
才能处理 才能负责更新这个 chunk
processed which were in charge of
updating that chunk that only those
将来只有那些 primaries 和 secondaries
primaries and secondaries are allowed to
可以在未来成为 chunk server
be chunk servers in the future and the
master 实现这个目的的方式就是使用版本号
way the master does this is with this
version number logic
master 告诉 primaries 和 secondaries
okay so the master tells the primaries
它们被允许修改这个 chunk
and secondaries that there it they're
allowed to modify this block
它还给 primary 一个租约 告诉primary
it also gives the primary a lease which
basically tells the primary look you're
在接下来的 60 秒内你将是 primary，60 秒后你就不再是
allowed to be primary for the next sixty
seconds after sixty seconds you have to
这个机制确保我们不会同时两个 primary，稍后我们再讨论
stop and this is part of the machinery
for making sure that we don't end up
这个机制确保我们不会同时两个 primary，稍后我们再讨论
with two primaries I'll talk about a bit later
okay 现在假设我们是 primary
okay so now we were primary now
master 告诉 client 谁是 primary 谁是secondary
the master tells the client who the
primary and the secondaries are and at
此时，我们正在执行论文中的图二
this point we're we're executing in
figure two in the paper the client now
client 现在知道谁是 primary 谁是 secondaries
knows who the primary secondaries are
client 的请求以某种秩序组织在一起 这篇论文
in some order or another and the paper
提出了一种聪明的方法来管理这种秩序
explains a sort of clever way to manage this
in some order or another the client
client 端将要追加的数据副本发送给 primary
sends a copy of the data it wants to be
appended to the primary and all the
和所有 secondaries 然后 primary 和
secondaries and the primary and the
secondaries 将该数据写入一个临时位置
secondaries write that data to a
此时这些数据并不会追加到文件中
temporary location it's not appended to
等 primary 和 secondaries 都收到数据并回复 yes 后
the file yet after they've all said yes
we have the data the client sends a
client 发送一条消息到 primary 说
message to the primary saying look you
你和所有 secondaries 节点都收到了我要追加的数据
know you and all the secondaries have
the data I'd like to append it for this file
primary 可能此时正从很多不同的 client 接收这些请求
the primary maybe is receiving these
requests from lots of different clients
这时 primary 会选择某种顺序依次执行所有 client 的请求 把数据追加到文件里
concurrently it picks some order execute
the client request one at a time and for
这时 primary 会选择某种顺序依次执行所有 client 的请求 把数据追加到文件里
each client appends request
primary 查看文件末尾的偏移量 也就是 chunk 的末尾
the primary looks at the offset that's the end of
the file the current end of the current chunk
确保 chunk 中有足够的剩余空间
makes sure there's enough
remaining space in the chunk and
然后将 client 记录写入当前块的末尾
then tells then writes the clients record to
the end of the current chunk and tells
并告诉所有 secondary 也将其写到末尾的相同偏移量处
all the secondaries to also write the
clients data to the end to the same
并告诉所有 secondary 也其写到末尾的相同偏移量处
offset the same offset in their chunks
primary 选一个偏移量
all right so the primary picks an offset
所有副本 包括primary 被告知在指定偏移位置追加新记录
all the replicas including the primary
are told to write
所有副本 包括primary 被告知在指定偏移位置追加新记录
the new appended record at at offset
这些 secondaries 它们可能会执行成功 也可能会失败
the secondaries they may do it they may not
比如说空间不足 或是崩溃
do it maybe run out of space maybe
they crashed maybe the network message
也可能是 primary 发送的消息在网络中丢失
was lost from the primary
如果 secondary 节点确实在这个偏移处
so if a secondary actually wrote the data to its
把数据写入了磁盘 它会回复 “yes” 给 primary
disk at that offset it will reply yes to
如果 primary 收到了所有 secondaries 回复的 yes
the primary if the primary collects a
yes answer from all of the secondaries
如果它们确实把数据写入了磁盘且向 primary 回复了 yes
so if they all of all of them managed to
actually write and reply to the primary
如果它们确实把数据写入了磁盘且向 primary 回复了 yes
saying yes I did it then the primary is
那么 primary 将向 client 端回复 success
going to reply reply success to the client
如果 primary 没有收到某一个 secondary 的回复
if the primary doesn't get an
answer from one of the secondaries
或是某个 secondary 回复了错误：
or the secondary reply sorry something bad
sorry 发生了一些不好的事情 我磁盘空间不足 我的磁盘挂了
happened I ran out of disk space my disk died
那么 primary 就会回复 no 给 client
I don't know what, then the primary
replies no to the client and the paper
论文说，如果 client 从 primary 得到这样的错误
says oh if the client gets an error like
that back in the primary the client is
client 应该重新发起整个追加的过程
supposed to reissue the entire append sequence
重新开始与 master 通信 以找出文件末尾
starting again talking to the
master to find out the most grease the
重新开始与 master 通信 以找出文件末尾
chunk at the end of the file
我想知道 client 端应该
I want to know the client supposed to
重新发起整个记录追加操作
reissue the whole record append
(提问) 你可能会这样想，但它们不会
operation ah you would think but they
所以问题让人很吃惊
don't so the question is jeez you know
你知道 primary 服务器告诉所有副本执行追加操作
the the primary tells all the replicas
也许其中一些服务器成功了 有些失败了
to do the append yeah maybe some of them
do some of them don't
如果其中一些失败 那么我们会向 client 端报错误
right if some of them don't then we
reply an error to the client
因此 client 认为 追加没有发生
so the client thinks oh the append didn't happen
但是其他副本的追加操作确实成功了
but those other replicas where the append
succeeded they did append so now we have
所有的副本都在追加相同的数据
replicas done on the same data one of them
但是其中之一返回了错误 它没有执行追加
the one that returned in error didn't do
the append and the ones they returned
而返回的 yes 的那些服务器确实做了追加
yes did do the append so that is just
这就是 GFS 运作的方式
the way GFS works
如果客户端随后读取了此文件
yeah so if a reader then reads this file
读取的结果取决于请求的是哪个副本
they depending on what replica they be
它们可能会看到追加的记录 也可能看不到
they may either see the appended record
or they may not if the record append
但是如果记录追加成功
but if the record append succeeded if
client 收到 success 成功消息
the client got a success message back
意味着所有副本 都以相同的偏移量追加了该记录
then that mean s all of the replicas
appended that record at the same offset
如果 client 得到 no 的回复
if the client gets a no back then zero
说明有 0 个或多个副本可能已经追加了该偏移量的记录
or more of the replicas may have
appended the record of that all set and
而其他副本则没有 所以 client 得到了 no
the other ones not so the client got a no
如果发生这种情况 会导致有些副本有记录 有些没有
then that means that some replicas
maybe some replicas have the record and some don't
所以你读取你可能读到 也可能读不到这个记录
so what you which were
所以你可能读到 也可能读不到这个记录
roughly read from you know you may or
may not see the record yeah
所有副本都是一样的
oh that all the replicas are the same
所有 secondaries 都有相同的版本号
all the secondaries are the same version
版本号仅在 master 分配新的 primary 时更改
number so the version number only
changes when the master assigns a new
你说的可能仅在 primary 出故障时才会发生
primary which would ordinarily happen
and probably only happen if the primary failed
所以我们讨论的都是具有新版本号的副本
so what we're talking about is is
replicas that have the fresh version number
你无法分辨出这些副本的区别
alright and you can't tell from
looking at them that they're missing
你无法分辨出这些副本的区别
that the replicas are different but
但可能他们就是有区别
maybe they're different and
这样做的理由是 可能不是所有副本都有那个追加记录
the justification for this is that yeah you
know maybe the replicas don't all have
这样做的理由是 可能不是所有副本都有那个追加记录
that the appended record but that's the
但是在这种情况下 primary 回答是 no
case in which the primary answer no to
并且 client 知道写入失败了
the clients and the client knows that
the write failed and the reasoning
这样做背后的原因是 client 将重新请求追加记录
behind this is that then the client
library will reissue the append
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
你知道 记录最终追加会成功
so the appended record will show up you know
eventually the append succeed you
因为 client 会继续发出（写请求）直到成功
would think because the client I'll keep
reissuing it until succeeds and then
当它成功时 追加记录的偏移量会在更远的位置
when it succeeds that means there's
gonna be some offset you know farther on
并且所有副本中的这个偏移位置都会有这个记录
the file where that record actually
occurs in all the replicas as well as
而那之前的偏移量位置 只有部分副本中才会出现追加的记录
offsets preceding that word only occurs
in a few of the replicas yes
oh，这是一个好问题
oh this is a great question
对于底层网络而言 数据传输路径可能非常重要
the exact path that the right data takes
might be quite important with respect to
对于底层网络而言 数据传输路径可能非常重要
the underlying network and the paper
论文在第一次提及时声称 client 把数据发送到每个副本
somewhere says even though when the
paper first talks about it he claims
论文在第一次提及时声称 client 把数据发送到每个副本
that the client sends the data to each
后来论文又改变说法 说 client 只把数据发送到离它最近的副本
replica in fact later on it changes the
tune and says the client sends it to
后来论文又改变说法 说 client 只把数据发送到离它最近的副本
only the closest of the replicas and
然后该副本将数据转发到另一个副本
then the replicas then that replica
forwards the data to another replica
沿着某种链路直到所有的副本都拿到数据
along I sort of chained until all the
replicas had the data and that path of
这条链路在整个数据中心上做过了最小化跨越交换机的处理
that chain is taken to sort of minimize
crossing bottleneck inter switch links
这条链路在整个数据中心上做过了最小化跨越交换机的处理
in a data center yes the version number
版本号只在 master 服务器认为没有 primary 时才会增加
only gets incremented if the master
thinks there's no primary so it's a so
在通常的流程中 那个 chunk 已经有一个 primary
in the ordinary sequence there already
be a primary for that chunk the the
master 会记得该 chunk 已经有一个 primary 和 secondary
the the master sort of will remember oh
gosh there's already a primary and
master 会记得该 chunk 已经有一个 primary 和 secondary
secondary for that chunk and it'll just
master 就不会再重新选择 primary 也就不会增加版本号
it won't go through this master
selection it won't increment the version
它只会告诉 client 端：看 这个是 primary
number it'll just tell the client look
up here's the primary with with no
这里没有发生版本号更改
version number change
我的理解是 如果是这样的话
my understanding is that if this is this
我想你是在问一个有趣的问题
I think you're asking a you're asking an
interesting question so in this scenario
在这种情况下，primary 向 client 端 回复失败消息
in which the primaries answered
failure to the client you might think
你可能会认为一定哪里出错了
something must be wrong with something
应该在继续进行之前将其修复
and that it should be fixed before you proceed
事实上 据我所知 论文里没有立即让 client 重试追加
in fact as far as I can tell the
paper there's no immediate anything the
事实上 据我所知 论文里没有立即让 client 重试追加
client retries the append you know
也许是因为网络消息丢失了
because maybe the problem was a network
所以没有什么可以修复的
message got lost so there's nothing to repair
本该传递出去的网络消息丢失了
right you know the network
message got lost we should be
重传网络消息的话这就有点复杂了
transmitted and this is sort of a
complicated way of retransmitting the
这种错误太常见了
network message maybe that's the most
common kind of failure in that case just
所以我们什么都不用改变
we don't change anything it's still the
如果还是相同的 primary，相同的 secondary
same primary same secondaries the client
client 的重试也许能正常工作
retries maybe this time it'll work
because the network doesn't
因为网络没有丢弃消息
discard a message it's an interesting
但是有意思的是 如果问题是某个 secondary 出现严重故障
question though that if what went wrong
here is that one of that there was a
但是有意思的是 如果问题是某个 secondary 出现严重故障
serious error or Fault in one of the secondaries
我们希望 master 服务器重新配置那组副本
what we would like is for
the master to reconfigure that set of
丢掉不工作的 secondary
replicas to drop that secondary that's
not working and it would then
master 会选择一个新的 primary 并递增版本号
because it's choosing a new primary in executing
this code path the master would then
master 会选择一个新的 primary 并递增版本号
increment the version and then we have a
接下来就有一组新的 primary、secondaries 和新版本号
new primary and new working secondaries
with a new version and this not-so-great
还有一个不太健康的 secondary，它包含的是旧版本和过期的副本
secondary with an old version and a
stale copy of the data but because that
因为它的版本比较旧 所以 master 永远不会将其误认为新版本
has an old version the master will never
never mistake it for being fresh
但是论文中没有证据表明 我说的这些会立即发生
but there's no evidence in the paper that
that happens immediately as far as
论文上说 client 只是重试并希望它稍后能正常工作
what's said in the paper the client just retries
and hopes it works again later
如果 secondary 挂了，最终 master 会 ping 所有的 chunk 服务器
eventually the master will
if the secondary is dead
如果 secondary 挂了，最终 master 会 ping 所有的 chunk 服务器
eventually the master does ping all the
并可能会定义新的 primary 和 secondary 的集合 并增加版本号
trunk servers will realize that and will
probably then change the set of
并可能会定义新的 primary 和 secondary 的集合 并增加版本号
primaries and secondaries and increment
但仅在（重试）以后
the version but only only later
(提问) 租约是解决这个问题的答案
the lease the leases that the answer to
如果 master 认为 primary 已经挂了怎么办，因为它无法访问到它
the question what if the master thinks
the primary is dead because it can't reach it
假设我们处于一种情况
right that's supposing we're in a situation
在某个时候 master 说，你是 primary
where at some point
the master said you're the primary and the
然后 master 对它们定期执行 ping 操作 检查它是否还活着
master was like pinging them all the
service periodically to see if they're alive
如果它挂了 master 就会选择一个新的primary
because if they're dead and wants
to pick a new primary the master sends
master 会向 primary 发送一些 ping 消息
some pings to you you're the primary and
如果某个时候 primary 没有回应
you don't respond right so you would
你肯定会觉得 上帝 这个 primary 没有回应我的 ping
think that at that point where gosh
you're not responding to my pings
如果你觉得 master 此时会先指定一个新的 primary 那就有问题了
then you might think the master at that point
would designate a new primary
如果你觉得 master 此时会先指定一个新的 primary 那就有问题了
it turns out that by itself is a mistake and
为什么？
the reason for that， the reason why it's a
如果你只是这样简单这样搞的话 就会出问题
mistake to do that simple did you know
use that simple design is that
master 去 ping primary 没有得到回复的原因
I may be pinging you and the reason why I'm not
getting responses is because then
可能仅仅就只是 master 和 primary 之间的网络有点问题
there's something wrong with a network
between me and you so there's a
primary 可能还活着，master ping 它，但是数据包在网络中丢失了
possibility that you're alive you're the
primary you're alive I'm pinging you the
primary 可能还活着，master ping 它，但是数据包在网络中丢失了
network is dropping that packets
master 此时可以与其他 client 通信
but you can talk to other clients and you're
并且正在处理其他 client 的请求
serving requests from other clients you know
如果 master 为那个 chunk 指定了​​一个新的 primary
and if I if I the master sort of
designated a new primary for that chunk
就会出现两个 primary 处理写 但是却又两个不同的数据拷贝
now we'd have two primaries processing writes
but two different copies of the data
最终会出现 2 个分道扬镳的数据
and so now we have totally
diverging copies the data and
这种具有两个 primary 处理请求
that's called that error having two primaries
且不知道彼此的错误的情况 称为脑裂
or whatever processing requests without
knowing each other it's called split brain
我在黑板上写出这个
and I'm writing this on board
这非常重要 它将会再次出现
because it's an important idea and
it'll come up again and it's caused or
这通常是由网络分区引起的
it's usually said to be caused by network
这是一种网络错误
partition that is some network error in
其中 master 服务器无法与 primary 服务器通信
which the master can't talk to the
但 primary 可以与 client 端通信
primary but the primary can talk to
这种部分网络故障 是构建这类存储系统中最难处理的问题之一
clients sort of partial network failure
and you know these are some of the these
这种部分网络故障 是构建这类存储系统中最难处理的问题之一
are the hardest problems to deal with
and building these kind of storage systems
好，那是问题所在
okay so that's the problem is
我们想避免为同一 chunk 错误地指定两个 primary 的情况
we want to rule out the possibility of
mistakingly designating two primaries
我们想避免为同一 chunk 错误地指定两个 primary 的情况
for the same chunk
master 采取的方式是 当它指定一个 primary 时建立一个租约
the way the master achieves that is that
when it designates a primary it says it gives a
master 采取的方式是 当它指定一个 primary 时建立一个租约
primary a lease which is basically the
租约是在一定时间内作为 primary 的权利
right to be primary until a certain time
master 记得租约持续多长时间
the master knows it remembers and knows
how long the least lasts and
并且 primary 知道租约能持续多久
the primary knows how long is lease lasts
如果租约到期，primary 就知道到期了 它就会停止执行 client 的请求
if the lease expires the primary knows that it
expires and will simply stop executing
租约到期后 它将忽略或拒绝 client 请求
client requests it'll ignore or reject
client requests after the lease expired
因此，如果 master 不能与 primary 通信
and therefore if the master can't talk
master 将会在租约到期后指定一个新的 primary
to the primary and the master would like
to designate a new primary
master 将会在租约到期后指定一个新的 primary
the master must wait for the lease to expire for
the previous primary so that means
master 必须要等待租约到期
master is going to sit on its hands for
60秒的租约到期后 可以确信旧的 primary 已经停止了它的角色
one lease period 60 seconds
after that it's guaranteed the old primary will
60秒的租约到期后 可以确信旧的 primary 已经停止了它的角色
stop operating its primary and now
那时候 master 就可以安全地指定新的 primary
the master can safely designate a new
而不会产生这种可怕的裂脑情况
primary without producing this terrible
split brain situation
(提问) 问题是说 为什么指定一个新的 primary 是坏的（设计）
oh so the question is why is designated
a new primary bad since the clients
既然 client 总是先问 master
always ask the master first and
master 改变主意后可先把 client 定向到新的 primary
so the master changes its mind then subsequent
clients will direct the clients to the new primary
原因之一是 client 会通过缓存提高效率
well one reason is that the
clients cache for efficiency the clients
client 会在短时间内缓存 primary 的身份信息
cache the identity of the primary for at
least for short periods of time
即使没有缓存，还有一种可怕的情况是这样的
even if they didn't though the bad sequence is
比如我是master，你问我 primary 是谁
that I'm the prime the master you ask me
我告诉你那个谁谁谁是是 primary
who the primary is I send you a message
saying the primary is server one right
该消息在网络中传递
and that message is inflate in the network
然后我发现 primary 出了故障
and then I'm the master I you know
I think somebody's failed whatever
然后我发现 primary 出了故障
I think that primary is filled
然后我又指定了个新的 primary
I designated a new primary and I send the
我发信息给你 说你是primary
primary message saying you're the primary
然后我开始回答其他 client 谁是这个 primary
and I start answering other
clients who ask the primary is saying
比如说那个服务器是 primary
that that over there is the primary
然而给你的信息仍在传递中
while the message to you is still in flight
你收到消息里的仍然是旧primary
you receive the message saying
你会觉得 我刚从 master 那里得到这个 primary 我要去和它通信
the old primaries the primary you think
gosh I just got this from the master I'm
你会觉得 我刚从 master 那里得到这个 primary 我要去和它通信
gonna go talk to that primary and
如果没有一些更聪明的机制
without some much more clever scheme
你不可能意识到（primary是旧的）
there's no way you could realize that
即使你刚刚从 master 那里获得了这些信息
even though you just got this
information from the master it's already
它也已经过时
out of date and if that primary serves
而且如果该 primary 接受了你的修改请求 回复你 success
your modification requests now we have
to and and respond success to you right
就会得到两个相互冲突的副本
then we have two conflicting replicas
(提问)
翻译: allen/adam (窃取成果追究法律责任)
翻译项目地址
https://github.com/ivanallen/thor
请再说一次。你有一个新文件，且没有备份
again you've a new file and no replicas
好的，如果你有一个新文件，没有备份
okay so if you have a new file no
甚至是已有文件，没有备份
replicas or even an existing file and no replicas
你将会执行一遍黑板上画的路线
the you'll take the path I drew
on the blackboard the master will
master 会收到 client 的要求说
receive a request from a client saying
我想追加这个文件
oh I'd like to append this file and
我猜 master 会首先发现
then well I guess the master will first
没有任何 chunk 与该文件关联
see there's no chunks associated with that file
它将创造一个新的 chunk 标识符
and it will just make up a new
chunk identifier or perhaps by calling
可能通过调用随机数生成器 然后在其块信息表中查看
the random number generator
and then it'll look in its chunk information
发现，天哪 我没有关于那个 chunk 的任何信息
table and see gosh I don't have any
information about that chunk and
于是它会创建一个新记录
it'll make up a new record saying but it must
它一定是一段特殊分支的代码
be special case code where it says well
我不知道任何版本号
I don't know any version number
这个 chunk 不存在，我要创建一个新的版本号1
this chunk doesn't exist I'm just gonna make
up a new version number one
再随机选择一个 primary 和一组 secondaries 并告诉它们
pick a random primary and set of secondaries
and tell them look you are responsible
你们对此新的空 chunk 负责，请开始工作
for this new empty chunk please get to work
论文说默认情况下 每个块有三个备份
the paper says three replicas per
通常是一个 primary 和两个 secondaries
chunk by default so typically a primary
and two backups
也许这里最重要的是重复我们几分钟前的讨论
okay okay so the maybe the most
important thing here is just to repeat
也许这里最重要的是重复我们几分钟前的讨论
the discussion we had a few minutes ago
GFS 是有意被创造的
the intentional construction of GFS
我们有这些追加的记录 且有三个备份
we had these record appends is that
if we have three we have three replicas you
client 可能会发送来一个记录 A 的追加
know maybe a client sends in and a
record appends for record A and
所有三个备份，primary 和两个 secondaries 成功追加了数据
all three replicas or the primary and both of the
secondaries successfully append the data
也许这个 chunk 中第一个记录是 A
the chunks and maybe the first record in
the chunk might be a in that case and
它们都一致，因为它们都执行了追加
they all agree because they all did it
假设另一个 client 进来说我要追加记录 B
supposing another client comes in says
look I want append record B
但消息传递给某个备份时丢失
but the message is lost to one of the replicas
因为网络某种错误
the network whatever supposably the
但另外两个备份拿到了消息
message by mistake but the other two
replicas get the message and
其中一个是 primary 另一个是 secondary
one of them's a primary and my other
它们都在文件中做了追加
secondaries they both append the file
所以现在我们有两个备份有记录
so now what we have is two the replicas
另一个没有任何记录
that B and the other one doesn't have anything
然后可能有第三个 client 想要追加 C
and then may be a third client
wants to append C and maybe the remember
记得这是 primary
that this is the primary
primary 选择偏移量并告诉 secondary
the primary picks the offset since the primary just
gonna tell the secondaries look
把记录 C 写在这个 chunk 里
write record C at this point in the
他们都在这里写C
chunk they all right C here
对于 B 的 client 来说
now the client for B the rule for a client for
它的请求收到 error 回复
B that for the client that gets us error
back from its request is that
它会重新发送请求
it will resend the request so now the client
因此现在要求追加记录 B 的客户端
that asked to append record B will ask
将再次请求追加记录 B
again to append record B and
也许这次信息没有在网络中丢失
this time maybe there's no network losses and all
所有三个备份追加了记录 B
three replicas append record B
对，这些备份都活着
right and they're all lives there they all
都拥有最新的版本号
have the most fresh version number and
如果 client 执行读的话
now if a client reads
读取到的内容取决于读取哪个副本
what they see depends on the chuck which
replicas they look at it's gonna see in
它将总共看到所有三个记录
total all three of the records but
但它会看到不同的顺序 具体取决于读取了哪个副本
it'll see in different orders depending on
which replica reads it'll mean
我会看到 A B C，然后一个重复的 B
I'll see A B C and then a repeat of B so
所以如果它读取此副本，将会看到B，然后C
if itreads this replica it'll see B and then C
如果它读取这个备份
if it reads this replica it'll see A
它会看到A，然后一个空白
and then a blank space in the file
然后是 C 然后是 B
padding and then C and then B so
所以如果你在这里读，你会看到 C，然后是 B
if you read here you see C then B
在这里你看到 B 然后 C
if you read here you see B and then C
不同的读请求会看到不同的结果
so different readers will see different results and
也许最糟糕的情况是
maybe the worst situation is it
一些 client 端从 primary 服务器收到错误
some client gets an error back from the
因为其中一个 secondary 未能执行追加操作
primary because one of the secondaries
因为其中一个 secondary 未能执行附加操作
failed to do the append and then
然后 client 端在重新发送请求之前挂掉
the client dies before we sending the
所以你可能进入这种情形
request so then you might get a
你的记录 D
situation where you have record D
出现在某些副本中 而在其他副本则完全没有
showing up in some of the replicas and
completely not showing up anywhere in
所以在这个方案下 primary 返回成功就具有很好的性质
the other replicas so you know under
this scheme we have good properties for
所以在这个方案下 primary 返回成功就具有很好的性质
for appends that the primary sent back a successful answer
但是对于 primary 返回失败的追加操作 就有点糟糕了
for and sort of not so
great properties for appends where the
但是对于 primary 返回失败的追加操作 就有点糟糕了
primary sent back of failure
追加的记录 副本都完全不同 一组完全不同的副本
and the records the replicas just absolutely be
different all different sets of replicas
(提问)
翻译: allen/adam (窃取成果追究法律责任)
翻译项目地址
https://github.com/ivanallen/thor
论文里说 client 从流程的最开始就开始
my reading in the paper is that the
client starts at the very beginning of
再次询问 master 该文件中的最后一个 chunk 是什么
the process and asked the master again
what's the last chunk in this file you know
因为如果其他人在文件中追加 这就可能会发生变化
because it might be might have
changed if other people are appending in the file
(提问)
翻译: allen/adam (窃取成果追究法律责任)
翻译项目地址
https://github.com/ivanallen/thor
我看不懂设计者心里想的啥
so I can't you know I can't read the
我认为该系统可以设计成使副本保持精确同步
designers mind so the observation is the
system could have been designed to keep
我认为该系统可以设计成使副本保持精确同步
the replicas in precise sync
这是真的，你将在实验 2 和 3 中实现它
it's absolutely true and you will do it in labs 2 & 3
你们将会设计一个进行复制的系统
so you guys are going to
design a system that does replication
它能真正的让副本保持同步
that actually keeps the replicas in sync
并且你将了解到 你需要采取多种技巧才能做到这一点
and you'll learn you know there's some
various techniques various things you
并且你将了解到 你需要采取多种技巧才能做到这一点
have to do in order to do that and
其中之一是 如果你希望副本保持同步 就必须遵循的一个规则
one of them is that there just has to be
this rule if you want the replicas to
其中之一是 如果你希望副本保持同步 就必须遵循的一个规则
stay in sync it has to be this rule that
规则是你不能将这种部分操作 仅应用于部分服务器 而不是所有服务器
you can't have these partial operations
that are applied to only some and not
这意味着必须有某种机制 即使 client 死了
others and that means that there has to
这意味着必须有某种机制
be some mechanism to like where the system
比如说 client 挂了，系统会说：等等，这个操作我还没完成
even if the client dies where the
system says wait a minute
比如说 client 挂了，系统会说：等等，这个操作我还没完成
there was this operation I haven't finished it yet
因此，你构建的系统中 primary 实际上要确保副本获得了每条消息
so you build systems in which the
primary actually make sure the backups
因此，你构建的系统中 primary 实际上要确保副本获得了每条消息
get every message
如果第一次写 B 失败
if the first right B failed you think
你认为 C 应该写在 B 的位置 然而它并没有
the C should go with the B
well it doesn't you may think it should
但是这个系统实际运行的方式是 primary 将 C 添加到 chunk 的末尾
but the way the system actually operates
is that the primary will add C to the
在 B 的后面
end of the chunk and the after B yeah I
这样做的原因之一是在写 C 的时候
mean one reason for this is that at the
time the right for C comes in the
primary 实际上可能不知道 B 的命运是什么
primary may not actually know what the
因为我们遇到了多个同时请求追加的 client
fate of B was because we met multiple
clients submitting appends concurrently
为了获得高性能
and you know for high performance
你希望 priamry 服务器启动执行 B 的追加操作
you want the primary to start the append for
一旦得知下一步结束 就告诉所有人把 C 写在那个offset之后
B first and then as soon as I can got
the next stop set tell everybody did you
这样所有这些事情就可以并行地发生
see so that all this stuff happens in parallel
通过减慢速度 primary 可以断定 B 完全失败了
you know by slowing it down you
could you know the primary could sort of
通过减慢速度 primary 可以断定 B 完全失败了
decide that B it totally failed and
然后发送另一轮消息请求撤消 B 的写操作
then send another round of messages saying
please undo the write of B and
那样会更复杂 更慢
there'll be more complex and slower I'm you know
同样 这样做的理由是 这个设计非常简单
again the the justification for this is
that the design is pretty simple it you know
但它会暴露给应用程序一些奇怪的东西
it reveals some odd things to applications
我们希望可以相对容易地编写应用程序
and the hope was that
applications could be relatively easily written
去容忍记录的顺序不同或别的
to tolerate records being in
different orders or who knows what or
如果他们不能容忍 应用程序可以
if they couldn't that applications could
要么自己安排选择一个顺序
either make their own arrangements for
picking an order themselves and
在文件或其他内容中写入你知道的序号
writing you know sequence numbers in the files
or something or you could just have a
如果应用程序真的对顺序非常敏感
if application really was very sensitive to
你就不应该从不同 client 端到同一文件的并发追加操作
order you could just not have concurrent
depends from different clients to the
你就不应该从不同 client 端到同一文件的并发追加操作
same file right you could just you know
对于顺序很重要的文件 例如说电影文件
files where order is very important
like say it's a movie file you know
你可不想把电影文件中的数据弄颠倒
you don't want to scramble
bytes in a movie file you just write the
那你就只用一个 client 连续地将电影写入文件
Movie file you write the movie to the
file by one client in sequential order
而不是并发地追加记录
and not with concurrent record appends
好
okay all right
有人问如何把这种设计 变成强一致性的系统
the somebody asked basically what would
it take to turn this design into one
有人问如何把这种设计 变成强一致性的系统
which actually provided strong
它的一致性更接近 我们的单服务器模型
consistency consistency closer to our
它不会让人产生令人吃惊的结果
sort of single server model where
there's no surprises I don't actually
实际上我不知道怎么做 因为这需要全新的复杂设计
know because you know that requires an
entire new complex design
目前尚不清楚如何将 GFS 变成这样
it's not clear how to mutate GFS to be that design
但我可以为你列出一些你需要考虑的事情
but I can list for you lists for you some
如果你想将 GFS 升级到强一致性系统
things that you would want to think
about if you wanted to upgrade GFS to a
如果你想将 GFS 升级到强一致性系统
assistance did have strong consistency
一个（要考虑的）是你可能
one is that you probably need the
需要让 primary 来检测重复的请求
primary to detect duplicate requests so
这样当第二个 B 到达 primary 能够知晓
that when this second B comes in the
primary is aware that oh actually you know
哦，实际上我们早些时候已看到了该请求
we already saw that request earlier
并且已经执行了或没有执行
and did it or didn't do it and to try to
并且要确保 B 不会在文件中出现两次
make sure that B doesn't show up twice
所以你需要具备检测重复的能力
in the file so one is you're gonna need duplicate detection
另一个问题 如果一个 secondary 扮演 secondary
another issues you
另一个问题 如果一个 secondary 就只是次要的
probably if a secondary is acting a secondary
你真的需要设计系统
you really need to design the system
（翻译：Allen, Adam）
（https://github.com/ivanallen/thor）
所以，如果 primary 告诉 secondary 做某事
so that if the primary tells a
secondary to do something
secondary 就必须得真的执行了 而不只是返回错误
the secondary actually does it and
doesn't just return error right
对于一个严格一致的系统
for a strictly consistent system having the
如果 secondary 能够随意终止 primary 请求而没有付出任何代价
secondaries be able to just sort of blow
off primary requests with really no
这样是不行的 所以我认为 secondary 必须接受并执行请求
compensation is not okay so I think the
secondaries have to accept requests and execute them
或者如果 secondary 磁盘有某种永久性损坏
or if a secondary has some
sort of permanent damage like it's disk
例如错误地拔出了磁盘
got unplugged by mistake this
你需要一种机制将 secondary 从系统中移除
you need to have a mechanism to like take the
secondary out of the system
这样 primary 可以和剩下的 secondary 继续工作
so the primary can proceed with the remaining secondaries
但这两点 GFS 都没有做 至少没有做对
but GFS kind of doesn't
either at least not right away
所以这也意味着 当 primary 要求 secondary 追加什么时
and so that also means that when the
when the primary asks secondary's to append something
secondary 必须小心不要将数据暴露给请求者
the secondaries have to be
careful not to expose that data to readers
直到 primary 确信所有 secondary 都能够执行追加操作为止
until the primary is sure that
all the secondaries really will be able
直到 primary 确信所有 secondary 都能够执行追加操作为止
to execute the append so you might need
因此你可能需要把写操作分成多个阶段
sort of multiple phases in the writes of
第一阶段，primary 请求 secondary
first phase in which the primary asks
我真的想让你执行此操作 你能执行此操作吗
the secondaries look you know I really
like you to do this operation can you do it
但此时 secondary 并不是真的执行此操作
but don't don't actually do it yet
如果所有 secondary 都答应能够进行操作
and if all the secondaries answer with a
promise to be able to do the operation
只有这个时候 primary 说
only then the primary says alright
好的去吧，这样每个 secondary 都将执行你所承诺的操作
everybody go ahead and do that operation
you promised and people you know
这是现实世界中很多强一致的系统的工作方式
that's the way a lot of real world systems
strong consistent systems work and that
这种技巧称为两阶段提交
trick it's called two-phase commit
另一个问题是，如果 primary 崩溃
another issue is that if the primary crashes
但已经有最后的一组 primary 发给 secondary 的操作开始了
there will have been some last
set of operations that the primary had
但已经有最后的一组 primary 发给 secondary 的操作开始了
launched started to the secondaries
而 primary 在确定所有 secondary 拿到拷贝之前就崩溃了
but the primary crashed before it was sure
whether those all the secondaries got
而 primary 在确定所有 secondary 拿到拷贝之前就崩溃了
there copied the operation or not
所以如果 primary 崩溃
so if the primary crashes you know
其中一个 secondary 将接任新的 primary
a new primary one of the secondaries is going
to take over as primary but at that
但是在那时 新的 primary 和其余的 secondary
point the second the new primary and the
remaining secondaries may differ in the
在最后的几次操作中可能会有所不同
last few operations because maybe some
因为也许其中一些在 primary 服务器崩溃之前没有收到消息
of them didn't get the message before
the primary crashed and so
因此，新的 primary 开始时必须与 secondary 显式地重新同步
the new primer has to start by explicitly
resynchronizing with the secondaries to
以确保他们的操作历史的最后几个步骤是一样的
make sure that the sort of the tail of
their operation histories are the same
最后，为了解决这个问题
finally to deal with this problem of oh
你知道 有时候 secondary 会有所不同
you know there may be times when the
或 client 可能会从 master 那里得到过时的指示
secondaries differ or the client may
have a slightly stale indication from
或 client 可能会从 master 那里得到过时的指示
the master of which secondary to talk to
所以 要么所有 client 都发送读请求给 primary
the system either needs to send all
client reads through the primary
因为只有 primary 才可能知道实际发生了哪些操作
because only the primary is likely to know which
operations have really happened
要么我们需要给 secondary 一个租约系统
or we need a lease system for the secondaries
就像 primary 那样
just like we have for the primary so
因此，众所周知
that it's well understood that when
当 secondary 能或不能合法回应 client 时
secondary can or can't legally respond
我要意识到这些事情必须在此系统中修复
a client and so these are the things I'm
aware of that would have to be fixed in this system
你需要更多复杂的技术使其具有强一致性
to added complexity and
chitchat to make it have strong consistency
你需要更多复杂的技术使其具有强一致性
and you're actually the way
我通过思考lab内容得到这份列表
I got that list was by thinking about the labs
你最终会做 我刚才所说的所有事情
you're gonna end up doing all
the things I just talked about as part
它是 lab2，lab3 的一部分
of labs two and three to build a
你需要建立严格一致的系统
strictly consistent system okay so
好吧，让我花一分钟的时间
let me spend one minute on there's actually
笔记中有一个链接
I have a link in the notes to a sort of
一个回顾性访谈，关于 GFS 在 Google 生涯的前五年或十年中表现的如何出色
retrospective interview about how well
GFS played out over the first five or
一个回顾性访谈，关于 GFS 在 Google 生涯的前五年或十年中表现的如何出色
ten years of his life at Google
最终的总结是 它取得了巨大的成功
so the high-level summary is that the most is
that was tremendously successful and
许多 Google 的应用都使用了它
many many Google applications used it in
许多 Google 基础架构 例如 BigTable 都构建在它之上
a number of Google infrastructure was
built as a layer like big file for
许多 Google 基础架构 例如 BigTable 都构建在它之上
example BigTable I mean was built as a
MapReduce 也是这样
layer on top of GFS and MapReduce also
它在 Google 被广泛使用
so widely used within Google
可能最严重的局限是
may be the most serious limitation is that
只有一个 master，它必须为每个 chunk 每个文件构造一个表条目
there was a single master and the master had
to have a table entry for every file and
这意味着随着 GFS 的使用量增加
every chunk and that mean does the GFS
它们涉及的文件越来越多
use grew and they're about more and more files
主机就用完了内存
the master just ran out of memory
用完了 RAM 来存储文件
ran out of RAM to store the files and
你可以增加更多的 RAM
you know you can put more RAM on but
但是一台计算机可以拥有多少 RAM 是有限度的
there's limits to how much RAM a single
machine can have and so that was the
因此这是人们遇到的最直接的问题
most of the most immediate problem
此外，单个 master 服务器上的负载来自成千上万个 client
people ran into in addition the load on
a single master from thousands of clients
这种情况越来越严重
started to be too much
在 master 中 cpu 每秒只能处理数百个请求
in the master only, the cpu can only
process however many hundreds of
特别是硬盘的写操作
requests per second especially the write
很快就会有过多的 client
things to disk and pretty soon there got
to be too many clients
另一个问题是 一些应用程序发现
another problem with a some applications found it hard
很难处理这种有点奇怪的语义
to deal with this kind of sort of odd
最后一个问题是
semantics and a final problem is that
master 服务器的故障切换并不是自动的
the master that was not an automatic
story for master failover
GFS 论文的原文里说需要人工干预
in the original in the GFS paper as we
read it like required human intervention
来处理已永久崩溃且需要更换的 master 主机
to deal with a master that had sort of
permanently crashed and needs to be replaced
那可能要花几十分钟甚至更长的时间
and that could take tens of
minutes or more I was just too long for
对于某些应用程序来说 这个故障恢复时间太长了
failure recovery for some applications
好极了，我们星期四见
okay excellent I'll see you on Thursday
我们将听到这个更多课程主题的信息
and we'll hear more about all these themes over the semester